地球，人類生命的發源地
Earth. Birth place of the human race.
人類與我們大致相近
A species much like our own.
在心懷仁慈的同時…
Capable of great compassion...
也充滿了暴力
and great violence.
我們在保護人類時
For in our quest to protect the humans,
解密了一些塵封的往事
a deeper revelation dawns.
原來我們與人類早已相識
Our worlds have met before.
這兒，這兒
Here, here.
變形金剛 Ⅱ：復仇之戰
Transformers: Revenge of The Fallen
（中國上海，當日22點14分）
發生在上海的爆炸性新聞
Breaking news at Shanghai.
上海市中心發佈一個大規模的有毒氣體洩露事故
There's been a major toxic spill on the Shanghai Central District.
市民們…今天
- Citizens today...  - For today,
我們會為大家關注事件的發展
we will bring you any new information
一旦有新的進展
our topic that's a developing story for you,
會立刻告訴大家…
as we get it...
（五角大樓 - 巢穴部隊指揮部）
情況怎麼樣？
What's the status?
海鷹正接近目標
C-hawks approaching target.
完成疏散還有三分鐘，長官
Three minutes until evacuation's complete, sir.
中國空域已封鎖，
Chinese airspace has been locked and sealed.
方圓一英里
One mile radius.
好的，巢穴部隊準備好開始行動
Alright, give NEST team the go.
黑鷹，可以著陸
Black Hawks, clear to land.
釘鈴鈴，出來拿你的冰淇淋
Ding-a-ling, come out and get your ice cream.
霸天虎都給我聽好了,等著被我打屁股吧
Any bad robot out there better get ready for ass-whooping.
過去兩年裏,我帶領一組新型汽車人
For the last two years, an advanced team of new Autobots
組成的先遣隊在這裏避難
has taken refuge here under my command.
阿爾茜雙胞胎，準備出發
Arcees, get ready to launch.
我們鎖定目標並著陸了
We're locked and loaded.
我們大家一起與人類結為盟友
Together, we form an alliance with the humans.
他們是一群勇敢的無名英雄
A secret, a brave squad of soldiers.
好的，夠了
Alright, that's enough.
媒體報道說是有毒物質洩漏
Time discovered story in this one is toxic spill.
是為了疏散人群進行搜救
They had to evac the area for search and rescue.
八個月內我們已對敵人作戰六次
This makes six enemy contacts in eight months.
這次行動決不能讓公眾知道
We gotta make sure this one does not get out the public axe
所以務必要保密
so keep it tight.
這支秘密部隊代號為「巢穴」
A classified strike team called NEST.
作戰目標鎖定我們汽車人的死敵,霸天虎
We hunt for what remains of our Decepticon foes,
突襲霸天虎在全球各地的巢穴
hiding in different countries around the globe.
從A區向E區挺進
Rolling Alpha through Echo now.
好的，鐵皮
Alright, Ironhide.
我們到達E區，走吧
We got Echo's. Vamos.
防守兩點鐘方向區域
To the stacks. Two o'clock.
他在這裏
He's here.
我聞到了
I smell him.
關上了，靠近了
It's close. It's heading closer.
哦，不
Oh, no.
怎麼樣？
How are ya?
有熱量存在
It's three ripple.
好的，大家都保持警惕
Alright, everybody, be steady.
它就在前面
We're right on top of it.
注意火力方向
Ease on fire.
黑豹一號，請求立即支援火力！
Hand to one. Requesting fire mission now!
直升機已就位，馬上趕到
Gunships on station. Rolling hot.
我們分離了一個
We intersected a Decepticon.
阿爾茜雙胞胎，目標朝你們來了
Arcee twins, target coming your way.
小心！
Watch out!
我搞砸了，還好，沒大礙
I screwed that up. I'm okay, I'm alright.
這可是作戰，你搞什麼東西？
This is kinda bad, man. What's wrong with you?
快讓橫炮上
Three insides white.
乾淨，迅速
Clear and fast.
媽的，我真棒
Damn, I'm good.
空中支援,現在就讓運輸機把它空降下來
Air support, we need Big Booter delivered and dropped now.
密碼，9-A…
Code 9-A...
下降倒數，五、四、三、二、一
Dropping in five, four, three, two, one.
汽車人，讓我來對付那傢伙
Autobots, I'm in pursuit.
還不快停下
Pull over.
弱不禁風的霸天虎
Punk-ass Decepticon,
有什麼遺言嗎？
any last words?
這個星球不是你們的地盤
This is not your planet to rule.
墮落金剛會東山再起的
The Fallen shall rise again.
看來會有麻煩
That doesn't sound good.
但今天不會
Not today.
快點，該走了，都出來吧
Come on, let's go. All hands on deck.
弗蘭克，魔腳，出去
Frankie, Mojo, out.
快點，孩子們
Come on, kiddo,
我們趕時間慢點，老爸
- we're on a schedule here.  - Slow down, Dad.
你這麼著急趕我走幹嘛，嗯？
Why are you in such a hurry to get rid of me, huh?
你把房間租出去了？
Did you rent the room out?
沒，不過我倒很想把你那房間
No, I got other ideas for your room
改造成家庭影院
and it rhymes with home theater.
看我找到了什麼,你小時候的嬰兒鞋
Look what I found. It's your little baby booties.
哦，老媽…
Oh, Ma...
我的寶貝兒子，兒子，你不能走
Oh my little baby, booty boy, you can't go.
你看到了嗎？
You see this?
這就是你們該有的反應
That's how you're supposed to react
親兒子就要踏入社會了,你們也要做好準備，行嗎？
when you free your loins does not uncool the world to pep for himself, okay?
行，你上大學我痛不欲生，鬱悶
Yeah, my heart... Please treat it about college, bummer.
記得常回家看看,任何假期都要回來
You have to come home every holiday,
別只是重大的節日才回來
not just big ones.
過萬聖節也回來
You have to come home for Halloween.
萬聖節我回不來，媽
I can't come home for Halloween, Mom.
那我們去看你
We'll come to you.
你們哪兒也別去
No, we're not going anywhere.
你化好妝，我們也會化了妝去的
You dress up, we'll be in costumes.
你們…你們不能那樣
You... You can't do that.
你讓孩子喘口氣，別哭了行嗎？
Would you let the kid breathe, for crying out loud?
快點，過來，裝行李！
Come on, go, pack!
真是不可思議你裝的行李
There's no way you're packed
就好像他要去旅行一個月，快點！
Time-chop. Let's go!
快點，去呀！
for a month long trip. Come on!
跑步前進，美女
March, young lady.
哦…爸！我好喜歡你叫我…
- Oh, oh, Dad!  - I love you when you call me
美女，虧你想得出來，老不正經
young lady, you dirty, old man.
不，你還什麼沒看到呢
Nah, you ain't seen nothing yet.
老爸，老爸，老爸，哇啊！
Dad, Dad, Dad, whoa!
怎麼了？
What?
我還在看著你們呢，老爸
I'm watching what you're doing, Dad.
這不是黃片啊
It's not a rap video.
教育不就是這樣的，不是嗎？
Just like a coach thing, you know.
我剛才都起雞皮疙瘩了，老爸
That's a really creepy move just now, Dad.
聽著，你是個英雄…
Look, you're the hero, uh...
你媽和我真的為你而感到驕傲
Your mother and me are really, really proud of you.
你是維基家族第一個上大學的
You're the first Witwiky ever to go to college.
現在我又想哭了，真是的！
Now I'm crying again. This sucks!
會沒事的，老媽
You're gonna be okay, Ma.
這對她來說有點…
Now this is going to be, uh...
你知道，難以接受…
You know, hard for her to...
自己兒子長大了，你知道
accept that her boy's all grown up, you know.
就要去自己闖世界了
Going out to handle the world on its own.
沒事吧，老爸？沒事
- You okay, Pop?  - Yeah.
魔腳，不許欺負弗蘭克！
Mojo, no dominating Frankie!
還不給我滾下來，你個野東西！
Get the hell of the couch, ya filthy beasts!
哇
Wow.
這種景像在大學裏隨處可見
You see a lot of that in college too.
爸，你說什麼呢？
What are you talking about, Dad?
你會碰見很多女孩子的
There's gonna be a lot of women there.
可我是個專一的人
Yeah, well, I'm the one-woman kind of guy.
聽著，米卡拉很棒
Look, Mikaela is the greatest,
但你們要給彼此留足空間，懂嗎？
but you gotta give each other room to grow, okay?
你們和其他小情侶沒什麼不同
You're no different than any other couple your age.
不過我們一起發現過外星人
Till we discovered an alien race together.
你們還能一起開那車多久？
How long are you gonna be riding that scooter?
爸，聽著，別人有可能分手
Dad, listen, I know what the odds are.
但我們是例外，知道了嗎？
We're the exception, okay?
等我一下…
Wait a second...
哦，你瞧這是誰？
Oh, who could that be?
兩周後就是另一個女孩打給你了
Two weeks, it could be Muffy.
嗨，美眉
Hey, beautiful.
我們分手吧，山姆真的嗎？
- I'm breaking up with you, Sam.  - Really?
你確定嗎？我覺得你沒下狠心啊
You sure? I hear a lot of conviction.
我下狠心了，行吧？
Well, I am, okay?
所以這一次我就不用來送你了
So there's no reason for me to come say goodbye to you.
哇啊，你這回是來真的
Wow, you almost sounded serious that time.
知道嗎？
Guess what?
我要送你一套異地戀愛裝備
I made you a long-distance relationship kit.
對，有個攝像頭,我們隨時都可以聊天
Yeah, I got you a webcam so we can chat 24/7.
愛你無處不在
All Witwicky all the time.
還有些上次戰鬥的紀念品
I got you a couple of souveniers
你說在電話裏不能說的
that you bet that cannot be mentioned on cellphone.
還有唱片啊，蠟燭什麼的…
Some mixes and candles and stuff...
真可愛，我等不及了
Sounds cute, I can't wait.
哦，嘿！
Oh, hey!
我那次穿過的T恤要嗎？
You want the infamous D-Day shirt?
那件破衣服還留著呢？
You kept your nasty, shredded clothes?
是啊，當然得留著，米卡拉
Yeah, of course I kept it, Mikaela.
這可是我的戰袍，浸透著鮮血啊
It's like my Superbowl jersey. I bled in this thing.
哇啊，你口氣不小呀，嗯？
Wow, you're pretty confident, huh?
不，不是那樣的
No, it's not that.
我向來沒什麼自信，剛才只是一個小高潮罷了
It's just that my low self-esteem's at an all-time high.
你以為那些個小紀念品
Do you think your little box of souveniers
就能留住我的心了
is gonna keep me from leaving you?
你真該和我一起走
You really should come with me,
學校旁邊房子很便宜
they got cheap apartments in campus.
哦，這個現在不太可能
Well, that's not gonna happen
除非我那不省心的老爸走上正道
until I get my man child father rushed out of prison,
能養活自己了才行
back on his feet.
我可聽著呢
I heard that.
離合器蓋子在哪兒？
Where did you put the clutch covers?
凸輪軸旁邊
Next to the cam shafts.
我就喜歡你說這術語，再說一遍
I love it when you say cam shafts. Whisper it to me.
凸輪軸
Cam shafts.
天，我對你恨不起來
God, I hate you.
這是家傳的魅力
It's my Witwicky charm.
喂，別掛，稍等一下
Wait, hold on. Wait, hold on a second.
我覺得我們不會分手
I guess we're not breaking up.
二十分鐘後見
I'll be over in 20.
米卡拉…
Mikaela...
我襯衫裏有塊方塊的碎片
I think this little bit Cube got stuck on my shirt.
山姆？
Sam?
哦，上帝！著火了！
Oh God! It's a fire!
老爸，著火了！
Dad, we got a fire!
著火了！
Fire!
羅恩，我怎麼知道會有
Ron, did you know it was gonna be
這麼難受？你別鬧行嗎？
- this hard?  - C-Can you just stop?
好，好，我不鬧等一下…
- Yeah, okay, I'll stop.  - Just wait...
你自己搬東西吧我會…我會…
- You carry this shit.  - I'll... I'll...
哇哦！知道嗎？
- Wow!  - You know what?
我哪兒都不跟你去
I don't wanna go anywhere with you.
我沒心情跟你去法國
I don't wanna go to France with you.
我連遛彎都懶得跟你去
I don't wanna go around the corner with you.
好，你行老娘回去看家去
- Alright, fine.  - I'm just going back inside.
那我自己去
I'll call you from Paris.
怎麼動靜這麼大？
What is all the racket?
哇啊山姆？
- Whoa.  - Sam?
哇，哇老爸…
- Whoa, whoa.  - Dad...
那是什麼玩意？廚衛用具！
- What was that?  - It's the whole kitchen!
救命…哦，我的…
Help me... Oh my...
大黃蜂！
Bumblebee!
哦，天啊！
Oh, jeez!
快點報警
Phone 9-1-1.
大黃蜂！回車庫去
Bumblebee! Get in the garage.
這些都是怎麼回事？
What the frick is happening?
到底怎麼了，兄弟？
What happened to restraint, man?
趕快進去，動作輕點行嗎？
Just go in the garage, quietly please?
我的媽呀！
Holy mother!
哦，我的天呀！
Oh, my God!
回…回車庫去，快！
I... In the garage, now!
沒電了！警察來了！
Power's out! Get the cops out!
快點，你們這些人，還在等什麼？
Come on, you guys. What are you waiting for?
我家房子著火了！
My house is on fire!
怎麼了？過來
- What happened?  - Come here.
聽著，我要你拿著這個方塊碎片
Listen, I need you to take the Cube sliver.
你拿著放錢包裏，快點
Put it in your purse, right now.
山姆·維基…我在，媽媽
- Sam Witwicky...  - Yes, Mom.
我有話說好
- A word with you.  - Yeah.
嗨，米卡拉你好
- Hi, Mikaela.  - Hi.
我這兒禿了哦
- I have a bald spot.  - Oh.
爐子太舊了，我猜是烤餅乾弄的
- An old furnace, I think.  - Become a waffle iron.
你走了，它也得走
When you go, he goes.
我不能讓個神經病機器人…住在我車庫裏
I cannot live with this psychotic alien in my garage.
朱迪，噓
Judy, shh.
國家機密
National security.
聽著，如果我們不吱聲,他們自然會擺平一切
Look, if we stay quiet, they're gonna take care of everything.
這一回就當是政府贊助我們重新裝修，好嗎？
Just consider this the official start of a remodel, okay?
好吧，如果是政府買單,那我要游泳池…
Fine. If the government's paying, I want a pool...
還有噴泉浴缸好的，行
- and a hot tub.  - Fine. Okay.
我要裸泳，你要有意見就死定了！
And I'm gonna skinny-dip and you can't say shit about it!
夥計，你有麻煩了
Yeah, you know you're a tool.
他嗓子有問題他在裝呢
- He's having voice problems.  - He's playing it up.
大黃蜂,我跟你說說上大學的事，好嗎？
Bee, I want to talk to you about the college thing, okay?
我好興奮啊！
I'm so excited!
嘿
Hey.
我不能帶你去
I'm not taking you with me.
我還是去外面吧，好吧？
I wanna wait outside, okay?
我本想早點告訴你
I wanted to tell you about this earlier.
只是…你知道
It's just that... You know,
是這樣
Here's the thing.
新生不允許有車
Freshmen aren't allowed to have cars.
要是我說了算，我肯定帶你去
I know, and if it was up to me, I'd take you with me,
可惜不行，大黃蜂
but it's not, Bee.
聽著，你是汽車人
Look, you're an Autobot.
你不該住在我爸的車庫裏
You shouldn't be living in my dad's garage.
我是說，你在這兒會憋壞的
I mean, you're suffocating in here.
你該呆在更好的地方的
You deserve better than this.
我很難受，兄弟
This is hard enough, man,
別讓我更難受，你就看著我好嗎？
don't make it harder. Can you just look at me, please?
別這樣，夥計
Come on, big guy.
聽著，你保鏢當得很好，對吧？你很盡職
Look, the guardian thing is done, okay? You did your job.
看，我現在安全了
Look, I'm safe now.
你應該回去找同伴們
You need to go be with Optimus Prime and the others.
我也想做普通人，大黃蜂
I just want to be normal, Bee.
所以我要上大學
That's why I'm going to college.
因此我不能帶你
I can't do that with you.
咱們也不是再也見不著面，夥計
It's not the last time I'm gonna see you, you know, Bee.
得了，別這樣，夥計,別逼我行嗎，大黃蜂
Come on, don't do that. Bee. You're killing me, Bee.
但你永遠是我的第一輛車
But you'll always be my first car.
我愛你，大黃蜂
Love you, Bee.
保險公司，納稅人，都會給我們補償的
Between state farm and the taxpayers, we're all taken care of.
你身上全是土不用，不用
- You got dirt all over you.  - Stop, stop.
什麼呀？我…不用擦
- What?  - It's...I'm okay.
哦，看
Well, look.
你覺得沒我
So you think you can make it
也可以度過大學幾年，是吧？
through those East Coast winners without me?
你的地位無人能及
You're like the best thing that ever happened to me.
然後呢？
And?
而且我願意付出一切
And I'll do anything for you.
然後呢？
And?
我想山姆馬上就要對她表白了
I think Sam's about to say the L word.
上啊，兒子
Let's go, kiddo.
真會挑時候，老爸
Nice timing, Dad.
我…喜歡你
I... adore you.
這不是我要聽的那個字
That's not the word that I wanna hear really now.
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
意思還不都一樣
It's the same word as the other word.
當然不一樣
It's not the same word.
聽著，我現在即便說了
Look, if I said the other word now,
也是你逼我說的
you forced me to say won't mean anything.
你也從沒說過那個字
Plus, you haven't said it either.
所以不許衝我發火
So don't get mad at me for not saying it.
對，我是沒說
Yeah, but I haven't said it
因為男生只想逃避責任
because guys always run when you say it first.
對，女生也一樣啊
Yeah, well, so do girls.
而且你又不怕沒人追
Especially, girls like you with options.
你為了不讓我離開
So this is all part of your elaborate plan
才故意不表白，是吧？
to keep me interested?
算是吧
Can be.
不是挺有效的嗎？
Ain't those working?
吻一下
Have a kiss.
我們可以的，我保證
We'll make it work, I promise.
那女人有方塊碎片，全體霸天虎注意，跟著她
Soundwave acknowledges. Pursue her.
奪回碎片
Retrieve it.
（「巢穴」部隊）
（迭戈·加西亞島軍事基地）
汽車人雙胞胎到三號機庫報到
Autobot twins, report to Hangar Three.
破冰淇淋車過來啦，借過，過一下
Excuse me, excuse me.
嗨，這晚上過的，是，寶貝，該升級了
Hello. What a night. Yeah, baby, it's upgrade time.
對，哦，對，看這兒，快點，就這兒
Yes, oh, yeah. Look here. Come on, let me call right here.
這不是我的老相好嘛
Time to get my sexy on.
綠的，我就知道
Green, I know,
綠的是我的，我要綠的
Green is mine, I call green
做我的身體吧
Be my body
我要綠色疼死我了
- I got the green.  - That hurt, man.
當然疼啦，踹的就是你
It's supposed to hurt. It's an ass kicking.
全體立正，蓋洛威顧問，幸會
Director Galloway, what an honor.
我本想帶你轉轉
Let me show you around
但你無權進入絕密區
but you gotta be in the classified access list.
現在可以了
I am now.
總統親自授權的，少校
Presidential order, Major.
我奉命帶話給你那些神秘的外星朋友
I got a message for your classified space buddies.
你們在上海的行動搞砸了
You guys made a mess at Shanghai.
對吧，所以上邊用來連線參謀長聯席會議
Alright, so this is where we communicate with the JCS.
而這片區域是汽車人的車庫
And this area serves as the Autobots' hangar.
與參謀長專線接通，少校
Secured line to JCS is up, Major.
（美軍軍用衛星）
現在是五角大樓安全專錢
Secured line to the Pentagon now.
看來上海的行動是艱難的一天啊
Saw the Shanghai op. It was a rough day.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
我有情報需要直接進行匯報
We have intel that I believe warns an immediate debrief.
你既然同意，我不能讓你看到他
Now with your permission, I can't let you see him
但我可以向你轉播擎天柱的聲音
but I would like you to hear from the leader of the Autobots.
開始吧
Proceed.
你肯定在想
You gotta wonder.
如果說上帝造了人，誰造了它？
God made us in his image. Who made him?
將軍，我們的聯軍，今年已打退霸天虎的六次入侵
General, our alliance has countermanded 6 Decepticon incursions this year.
在每個大洲都有交手
Each on a different continent.
他們肯定是在找尋什麼
They're clearly searching around the world for something.
但昨晚我們消滅的霸天虎，留了這麼一句狠話：
But last night's encounter came with a warning:
「墮落金剛還會東山再起的」
The Fallen shall rise again.
「墮落金剛」，什麼意思？
"The Fallen." Meaning what?
來源：不清楚
Origin: Unknown.
所有的歷史
They only recorded
我們變形金剛所有的歷史，只記載於火種源之中
history of our race was contained within the All-Spark,
也隨之一同毀滅
lost with its destruction.
我插一句！
Excuse me!
既然你所說的那個火種源現在毀滅了
If this so-called "All-Spark", now destroyed,
那敵人為何沒按你預想…
why hasn't the enemy left the planet
離開地球呢？
like you thought they would?
蓋洛威先生，是美國國家安全顧問
Director Galloway, our national security advisor
總統派他負責聯絡
the President just appointed him liasion.
這太…我怎麼沒有得到通知
- It's too, uh...  - Well, I guess I didn't get that memo.
很抱歉打斷你，將軍，借過，讓一下
Forgive the interruption, General. Excuse me, coming through.
借過，借過…
Excuse me, excuse me...
上海的那次行動造成很大損失
After all the damage in Shanghai,
總統…
the President is, uh...
勉強宣佈行動成功
hard-pressed to say the job's getting done.
如今，我們有「外星汽車人合作秘密法案」定下合作框架
Now under the classified Alien Autobot Cooperation Act,
你們雖然同意與我們共享情報
you are agreeing to share your intel with us,
但從不共享先進武器
but not your advancements in weaponry.
我們已目睹你們人類的好戰本性
We've witnessed your human capacity for war.
給你們的話，結果必將會弊大於利
It would absolutely bring more harm than good.
什麼時候輪到你替我們考慮了？
But who are you to judge what's best for us?
原諒我插一句，我們和汽車人
With all due respect, we've been fighting side-by-side
並肩作戰有兩年了
in the field for two years.
我們出生入死，一同流血流汗
We've shared blood, sweat and precious metal together.
士兵，打你的仗去，少插嘴
Soldier, you're paid to shoot; not talk.
你別惹我
Don't tell me.
而且…
And the, uh...
汽車人又來一撥放鬆…
- The newest members of your team...  - Easy...
我知道你們是向太空中的汽車人發送了訊息
I understand they arrived here after you sent a message into space.
公開邀請他們來到地球
An open invitation to come to Earth,
但從未讓政府審核過
embedded by no one at the White House.
我先打斷你一下，蓋洛威先生
Let me stop you right there, Mr. Galloway.
審核就在此進行
It was bedded right here.
而據我所知，倫諾克少校和戰友們作出的判斷
And in my experience, the judgement of both Major Lennox and his team,
總是準確的
has always been above reproach.
好，即便如此，將軍，總統認為
Well be that as it may, General, it is the position of the President
眼下國家安全形勢嚴峻
that when our national security is at stake,
沒有人能保證做到完美
no one is above reproach.
我們不妨先回顧一下？
Now, what do we know so far?
我們知道霸天虎的頭領
We know that the enemy leader,
代號NBE-1，又被稱作威震天
classified NBE-1, AKA Megatron,
早就銹成了廢鐵
is resting in peace
埋於勞倫森海溝深處
at the bottom of the Laurentian Abyss,
處於聲納監聽系統和潛水艇
surrounded by societs detection nets
全天候的重重監控
and a full-time submarine surveillance.
我們還知道
We also know that
火種源的唯一殘片
the only remaining piece of your alien All-Spark
正保存在電磁保險庫裏
is locked in an electromagnetic vault,
而這個保險庫在全世界最安全的海軍基地裏
here on one of the most secure naval bases in the world.
而雖然沒人…
And since no one...
能不能告訴我敵人現在究竟在找什麼
can seem to tell me what the enemy is now after,
但我…至少能猜出大概
well, there...there's only one clear conclusion:
就是你們，汽車人
You.The Autobots.
他們是來追殺你們的
They're here to hunt you.
不然他們來地球還能為了什麼？
What's there to hunt for on Earth besides that?
「墮落金剛…要東山再起」？
"The Fallen... shall rise again"?
聽上去確實要出大事
Sounds to me like something's coming.
那麼我想問一下,如果我們最終認定
So let me ask if we ultimately conclude
你們只有離開地球避難
that our national security is best served
才能確保地球的安全
by denying you further asylum on our planet,
你們會和平地離開嗎？
will you leave peacefully?
你們應享有自由
Freedom is your right.
你們如果那樣要求,我們會尊重你們的要求
If you make that request, we will honor it.
不過，在你們總統下決定前,請你問問他
But before your president decides, please ask him this.
如果你們錯了，有後悔藥吃嗎？
What if we leave and you're wrong?
問得好
That's a good question.
哦，我的天啊
Oh, my God,
你看看這地方！
just look at this place!
感覺自己已經變聰明了
I feel smarter already.
羅恩，你聞到了嗎？
Ron, can you smell it?
對，每年四萬塊的學費
Yes, smells like $40, 000 a year.
好吧，真摳門
Okay, cheapo.
你先去吧，我們…我們來搬
Go ahead, we'll, uh... We'll get your stuff.
你去看看宿舍就行
Just go ahead and check out your room.
嘿嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
你是山姆吧？我是裏奧
You must be Sam, right? I'm Leo.
你好
Hey.
哦，對不起，我先住上了
Uh, sorry, I already set up the crib.
你想睡哪一邊？
Do you want this side or that side?
那邊我已經選那邊了
- That side.  - I already chose that side.
你什麼意思？這很令人難堪
You know what this is? This is the awkward moment.
對，你怕我不正常
Yeah, so you're trying to see if I'm a normal guy.
我也怕你不正常
I'm trying to see if you're a normal guy,
沒道理，一身病，老是惹到我
balanced and medicated enough for another coral space.
你講究衛生我就死不了
Good personal hygiene won't stab me in my sleep.
沒犯罪記錄，從不偷東西
Good criminal record won't steal anything.
沒搶過女朋友特別是這條
- Including girlfriends.  - Especially girlfriends.
有女朋友了嗎？當然
- You got a girlfriend?  - I do.
你呢？不，還沒有
- You?  - No, not a chance.
喜歡電腦嗎？
You're a techie?
很好
Sweet.
沙斯基，法斯賓德，怎麼樣了？
Sharsky, Fassbiner, where we at?
服務器上線了，裏奧
Server's almost online, Leo.
網絡可以用了
It works up and running.
非常好，我就想聽這個
Beautiful, that's what I like to hear.
那是沙斯基，這是法斯賓德
That's Sharsky, that's Spastik
嘿，兄弟
Hey, dude.
我的IT顧問
my I.T. gurus.
歡迎訪問我的網站，兄弟
Welcome to my empire, bro.
真實的世界.com
TheRealEffinDeal.com.
就是我，你肯定聽說過
That's me, I'm sure you've heard of it.
不，沒聽過真差勁
- No, I haven't.  - Well, that sucks.
是什麼網站？聽著，看…
- What is all this for?  - See, look...
我挺俗的，我想當年輕的百萬富翁
Call me gross, I wanna be a baby billionaire.
小貓咪日曆
Kitten calendars.
從這裏起步，你看著我
It's where it started. Look at me now.
要有夢想，老兄
Got our dreams, bro.
裏奧，上海那邊有壞消息
Leo, we got some bad news in Shanghai.
貼網上，寶貝，快，快，快！
Post it, baby. Go, go, go!
澆點油，好極了！
FTJ, FTJ!
很清楚澆什麼油？
- It's clean.  - What's FTJ?
- 火上澆油，火上澆油
- 澆點油，澆油
- Fuel the Jet, Fuel the Jet.  - FTJ, FTJ.
就是這個，看到了嗎？
This is it. Did you see that?
哇，好的，上海得有一半…
Wow. Okay, this half of Shanghai
被洩露到了，當中國說是毒氣洩漏
gets rigged when China says gas leak.
肯定騙人的，兄弟
Don't believe the hype, bro.
兩年前在洛杉磯,外星人對戰也沒報道
Just like the alien robots in LA two years ago that everyone covered up.
對，我親眼所見，他們大開殺戒
Yeah, I saw these robots and they did this, like,
從天而降，噴火燒活人
firing thing and they came down and twisted this woman
就好像…這是假的吧
- and she was like...  - Looks fake to me.
哥們，怎麼可能,網上的東西絕對真實
Dude, it's not fake. The Internet's pure true.
視頻不說謊太假了
- Neither does it lie.  - It looks fake.
不，兄弟，我看見他們
No, man, I've seen them.
他們就像這樣…機器人…
They are like these, uh, robots...
看，看，看，是假的
Look, look, look, it's fake.
誰都可以用電腦做，對吧？
Anybody can do on any computer, okay?
我又沒…沒在場
And I wasn't, uh... there.
所以我不能評論或猜測
So I can't comment or speculate.
哦，不「評論或猜測」？
- Oh, no.  - "Comment and speculate"?
你還是我室友嗎？
We're supposed to go habitate?
不，聽著，好吧，別相信那些東西，兄弟
No, listen, okay. Don't be sucking the sack, bro.
什麼啊？胡言亂語啊
- Whose sack?  - Look, the ball sack.
老兄，你火星來的啊？主流媒體胡說
- Dude, what kind of tool are you?  - Mainstream media sack.
它們在撒謊，知道吧
They're lying to us, alright.
真的是外星人好吧，好吧
- It's aliens, man.  - Okay, okay.
跟我來
Follow me.
裏奧，壞了，咱們晚了一步
Uh-oh. Uh, Leo. Bad news, we just got scooped.
機器巨人網上早就有了
The video's already up on GeoBoard.
媽的…不是吧！
Damn... No!
機器戰士老跟我們搶獨家新聞
Robo-Warrior has a main competition, our conspiracy step.
連我網站的名字他都敢抄
Effing was my effing idea. He stole it.
他鏈接到我網站，瘋狂抄襲稿件！
He's been looking to my site and thieving hits for ever!
對了，我看過你檔案
By the way, I read your file.
我會上傳，你也上傳…一起奮鬥吧？
I'll pour, you'll pour... We're gonna fix that, alright?
你被錄用了
You work for me, now.
我被你錄用？
I work for you now?
開玩笑，我剛上大學
That's incredible. It's first day of college,
就供職於一家破網絡公司
I got a career, a dinky internet firm,
老闆人倒不壞，還真把自己當回事了
with a boss who is made up of just pure champion stuff.
你嘲笑我的心血是吧，薩姆爾？
You're mocking my life's work, Samuel? Huh?
先警告你這張嘴，兄弟
That's your one warning patrolling, dude.
別逼我…不然我讓他盜你補助帳戶
Don't make me that fast.... 'cause I'll do it.
嗨，好吧，聽著，這房間我住不慣
Hey alright, listen. It's getting a little intense in my room.
能換嗎？看你的臉，３１２
- Can I switch now?  - Oh, sad face, 3-12.
不退不換，別老皺著眉頭，行嗎？
No switching, no treating. Let's turn that upside-down, okay?
哦，到了到了，嗨！
- Oh, here we go.  - Hey, hi.
就像霍格沃茨魔法學校，嗨！
It's just like Hogwarts. Hi!
男女混住？這裏男女混住？
Is this co-ed? This is a co-ed dorm.
想見見我室友嗎？
Do you guys want to meet my roommates?
好呀他們很不錯
- Yeah.  - 'Cause they're real swell guys.
這是裏奧我們是維基家族
- Here is Leo.  - We're the Witwicky.
我叫裏奧我叫朱迪
- I'm Leo.  - I'm Judy.
嘿，你有個好兒子，他非常棒
Hey, you have a great son. You really do.
哦，你不是最乖的嗎？
Oh, well aren't you the sweetest thing?
他確實最乖，媽
He's real sweet, Ma.
對了，你手裏拿的是什麼啊？
What is that in your hand, by the way?
哦，他們賣我的炒貨，為環保義賣的
Oh, I got this at the bake sale for the environment
那幫男生做的
that those boys were having.
你知道吧，很少有白人男孩
You know, you don't often see white boys
留長髮而且還扎辮子呢
with the dreadlocks.
媽，對，這是百分之百的夏威夷純
- Mom.  - Yeah, it's a 100 percent pure Hawaiian
天然的環保食品。朱迪…能扔掉嗎？
- green for the environment.  - Jud... Can you please drop it?
對，因為他們在裏頭摻入了大麻
Yeah, then they baked it with reefer in it.
不，這是我…嘿！快給我
- No, it's canna... Hey!  - Please give me.
嘿！我今天不節食，想吃就吃
Hey! It's my cheap day. I can eat whatever I want.
天，我要瘋了，快做點什麼，爸
Please God, I'm gonna freak out. Please do something right now, Dad.
拜託做點什麼好了，好了
- Please do something right now.  - Okay, okay.
走開，你這個長髮瘋子！
Out of my way, you wild hair!
巧克力餅我想吃多少吃多少！
I can eat all the freaking brownies I want!
抱歉，夥計們
Sorry, fellas.
抱歉，沒什麼的
I'm sorry and you're welcome.
這兒雲集全校美女
We call it the Hot Freshmen 55.
這是女新生前五十五強
Sharsky hacked campus house and
沙斯基修改了住宿分配系統，調來全部美女
stacked the dorm with pretty beddies.
我的天，是她
Oh, my God. It's her.
她來了，她看我了，她看我了
She's coming. She sees me, she sees me.
這個姑娘是我的最愛
She's tight for me on one on my to-do list.
你可不許搶，聽到了嗎？
Do not bird-dog my credit, you hear me?
你們真漂亮
Pretty girls.
嘿，你好，我兒子住這個房間
Hey, you. My son lives in this dorm.
你該和他交個朋友
You should go make friends with him,
- 他是爸爸
- 真希望她不是我媽
- he's bad.  - Bless she ain't my mama.
他最近剛剛告別處男
And he recently had his cherry popped.
他不知道我當時在家
He didn't know I was in the house.
我全聽到了嘿，嘿，嘿
- I heard it all.  - Hey, hey, hey.
就是他！
There he is!
哦，我該把他打扮成歌壇第一帥的小天王吧？
Oh, will you give him my closet?
嘿，他那輛車還是個會說話的機器人！
Hey, and his car is a talking robot!
不是，其實是個…GPS導航儀，導航儀
No, like a... like a GPS, All-Star.
噢導航儀
- Okay.  - All-Star.
飛盤，哇！
Frisbee. Whoo!
不，老爸
No, Dad.
老爸，你帶她到處轉轉
Dad, you're just gonna let her run around school.
你還好嗎？哇啊
- Are you alright?  - Whoa.
給我
Give me.
你瘋了嗎？
Are you crazy?
朱迪，朱迪，放下它，放下它
Judy, Judy. Just... Just put it. Just put it.
看好你母親
You gotta control your mother.
我不認識她
I wasn't doing this.
嘿，老教授，只要給我A，做什麼都行
Hey, Professor. I'd do anything for an A.
行啊，壞丫頭…
Alright, Grace...
車上有吃的，我們走
Looks like we got some snacks in the car. Let's go.
哇！那雙小鞋呢？
- Whoo!  - Did you gt the booties?
對，爸，我拿著呢！
Yes, Dad, I got the booties!
- 好吧，好吧
- 哦，我的天，我倒個兒了！
- Alright, alright.  - Oh my God, I'm upside-down!
（軍事禁區）
黑獅放射線，我是黑獅探戈
Black Light in X-Trait. This is Black Light in Tango.
我區邊界西部感應到異常活動，B14區被侵入
Breach in B-14.
快，快，快，快，快！
Go, go, go, go, go!
殘片沒了
The Shard is gone.
幹掉它！
Take him down!
開火趴下！
- Open fire.  - Get down!
這可是兄弟會的第一次派對
The first frat party's the game change of boys,
漂亮姑娘成堆，大伙都痛快地玩
we're hunting in the wild now, so get your game faces on.
我不能呆太久，我待會還要和女友視頻聊天
I can't stay long, I have a webcam date with my girlfriend.
太酷了哪有
- That's so cool.  - No, it's not.
你就抱著屏幕親吧
While he's making up with his MacBook,
今晚我可要玩真的了
I'm gonna be dating my spitzy, freaky freak on.
我們走瞧她的身材
- Let's roll.  - She's hot.
我們…去泡妞了
We're, uh... We're hunting.
我走了，寶貝再見，爸爸
- See you, darling.  - Bye, Dad.
好的
Okay.
（米卡拉，正在連線…山姆）
我們頭一回網聊，以前從沒有過
This is our first live chat date. Never done it before.
我有點緊張了
I'm kind of nervous.
你沒事吧？沒事…
- Are you okay?  - No, uh...
我來拿餐巾紙的
I was getting a napkin for my drink.
謝謝，乾杯！
Thanks. Cheers!
你叫山姆，對嗎？對
- You're Sam, right?  - Yeah.
跳支舞吧
I wanna dance.
要跳舞？
Like... Like dancing?
像一對？像雙人舞，像情侶那樣？
Like a pairing? Like a duo, like a coupling?
我已經有女朋友了…
'Cause I'm in a permanently, semi...
- 反正我有女朋友了
- 哦，別緊張
- I'm in a relationship, kind of.  - Oh, relax.
大家高興一下嘛
I just want to have some fun.
哦，要高興一下？哦，那好吧
Oh, just some fun? Oh yeah, okay.
我們下棋吧，你坐在那邊，然後…
Let's play some checkers. You can sit over there, and, uh...
哦，我的天這樣吧，今晚
- Oh my God.  - So how about tonight,
我假裝是你女朋友
you pretend I'm your girlfriend
你假裝是我男朋友
and I pretend that you're my boyfriend.
（山姆不在線）
嘿！外面草坪上那輛跑車是誰的？
Hey! Who broke the frickin' yellow Camaro?
嗯？車堵住門口了
Huh? There's a car on the run.
你來幹嘛？
What are you doing?
休斯頓，我們有麻煩了
Houston, we have a problem.
怎麼了？新來的！
- What is it?  -  Freshman!
對那是你的車嗎？
- Yeah.  - Is that your car on our bushes?
不，這是我朋友的，他剛去…
No, there's a friend of mine who just went to a...
換衣服了
who went to get you a tighter shirt.
換個鬼，我們查過了
There isn't a tighter shirt. We checked.
想讓我踢你屁股嗎？
Now how about I park my foot in your ass?
你的腳多少碼？
What size shoe do you wear?
- 哦，我看你真是…
- 慢著，慢著…！
- Yeah, oh, you ain't...  - Hold on, hold... Whoa!
你…你是不是想？
Are you... Are you trying?
我馬上就回來
I'm gonna back it up right now.
出來
Get it out of here.
你還有車？
You have a ride?
兄弟，你竟然不告訴我們？
Bro, why you holding onto us?
我才剛認識你17小時
I've only known you 17 hours.
這會改變我們的生活的
This is gonna really change our lives.
你無法想像
You have no idea.
我喜歡跑車
I love Camaros.
哦，聽好，現在不行，好嗎？
I can't do this right now, okay?
你怕什麼
Don't be a wimp.
哦，天哪
Oh, God.
- 我第一輛車是我爸的九二版Ｚ２８
- 是嗎？
- My first car was my Dad's money 2Z-28.  - Yeah?
加滿油後
Fuel-injected.
引擎的咆哮聲讓我渾身興奮
The roar of the engine. It just, tickles me.
我們…還沒…我是說，發展到…
We shouldn't, uh, stare... I mean, share stories...
那種地步吧
to each other at all.
你怎麼了，山姆？就帶我一程…
What're you becoming, Sam? Just one ride...
停下，停下
Don't. Don't.
收音機壞了吧？
Is your radio broke?
- 不，我腦子壞了
- 我們沒出軌
- No, my car's iteration is.  - We're not cheating.
還沒呢
Not yet.
這是怎麼了？
Something wrong here?
哇！哦，天哪！你沒事吧？
Ow! Oh, God! You okay?
我真不知道該怎麼跟你說
I really don't know what to tell you,
這車…毛病很多
this car... It just has a lot of problems.
很多…
A lot of prob...
哦，天哪，哦，進嘴裏了，哦…
Oh, God. Oh, it's in my mouth. Oh...
你沒事吧？
Are you okay?
我有紙巾，紙巾擦擦臉
I got wetnaps. I got wetnaps for your face.
等等
Hold on.
真對不起！
I'm so sorry!
你想怎樣？
What are you doing?
一天都不讓我安寧，嗯？
You won't give me a day, huh?
- 這可是我第一天入學
- 非常抱歉，山姆
- You won't give me one day in college.  - I'm sorry, Sam.
但火種源最後一塊殘片還是被偷了
But the last fragment of the All-Spark was stolen.
什麼？霸天虎干的嗎？
Like what? Like Decepticon-stolen?
我們按照要求將殘片交給人類的政府保管
We placed it under human protection at your government's request.
但我在這兒是幫助你的，山姆
But I'm here for your help, Sam.
因為你們的領導者認為
Because your leaders believed
我們把仇恨轉嫁到了地球上
we brought vengeance upon your planet.
或許，他們是對的
Perhaps, they are right.
但必須要有一個雙方都信任的人
That is why they must be reminded by another human
來時常提醒他們
of the trust we share.
這不是我的戰爭還不是
- This isn't my war.  - Not yet.
但我恐怖很快就會是了
But I fear it soon will be.
地球一定不能像塞伯坦星球那樣
Your world must not share the same fate as Cybertron.
致使萬物流離失所
Whole generations lost.
我知道我…我想幫助你，真的
I know and I... I want to help you. I do.
但我不是你們駐地球的大使
But I'm not some alien ambassador.
你知道，我只是一個普通人
You know, I'm a normal kid with normal problems.
我做我該做的事
I am where I'm supposed to be.
對不起，我…
I'm sorry, I...
我真的很抱歉
I really am.
山姆，我們不能指望天意來改變自己的命運
Sam, fate rarely calls upon us at a moment of our choosing.
你是無敵的擎天柱，你不需要我
You're Optimus Prime. You don't need me.
需要…只是你不知道而已
We do... more than you know.
（北大西洋 - 早上7點13分）
方向２- １
- ４，有可疑目標接近
New contact, bearing 214 and possible hostile
（美國船舶托皮卡號核潛艇 - 754）
威震天在深海所處位置
confirmed for Project Beat Six drop-point.
怎麼樣了？有五個目標
- What you got?  - Sue, pull five contacts.
已迅速潛至水下五千英尺
5,000 feet. Diving fast.
我從沒見過下潛這麼快的
There's something. They dive that deep, that fast.
- 進入戰鬥狀態
- 傳令，進入戰鬥狀態
- Man battle stations.  - Sealer One, man battle stations.
快，左滿舵，速度三分之二
Hell, not pull the rudder or head two-thirds.
下潛，下潛
Dive, Cookie.
檢測到敵方正發出聲波，上官
The NEST protecting NBE-1 are screening, sir.
此處深達九千三百英尋
That is 9,300 fathoms down.
- 沒有深潛器能趕到現場嗎？
- 沒有，長官
- And no confirmed DSRVs on sight?  - None, sir.
那麼各位，麻煩大了
Then, people, we've got a problem.
需要零件
Need parts.
拆掉最小的那個
Kill such little one.
有碎片就有能量晶體
Sea shard, make Energon.
收到，聲納探測到六個敵人正快速靠近
Prime sonar now holds six contacts and they're coming up fast.
馬上發碰撞警告…
Man collisional arm...
…距離五百英尺
...are 500 feet.
我們離開這裏
Let's get out of here.
天使六號
Angel Six,
有六個敵人進犯
we got six hostiles coming down.
準備撞擊，側翼…距離一百英尺
- Collision imminent. Portside...  - 100 feet.
準備撞擊
Brace for impact.
紅蜘蛛，我回來了
Starscream, I'm home.
威震天殿下，看到你恢復
Behold, Megatron, I was so relieved
神速…我就放心了
to hear of your... resurrection.
你竟然把我扔在這個垃圾星球上見死不救
You left me to die, you pathetic insect!
不，我是在擴充新的隊伍
Only to help spawn our new army,
墮落金剛也很生氣，畢竟你不在
the Fallen decreased it, after all, in your absence,
總得有人來統領大局吧
someone had to take command.
你…
You...
太讓我失望了
are so disappointing.
即便我死了，也輪不到別人發號施令
Even in death, there's no command but mine.
我的主人，此行我辜負了你
My master, I failed you on Earth.
火種源被摧毀了
The All-Spark is destroyed,
沒有它，我們的種族遲早滅亡
and without it, our race will perish.
你還有很多要學，我的傻徒弟
You have much to learn, my disciple.
方塊只不過是個容器
The Cube is merely a vessel.
它的能量和真諦永不會被摧毀
It's power, it's knowledge can never be destroyed.
只不過變換了形態
It can only transform.
這是怎麼回事？
How is that possible?
方塊的能量…
It has been absorbed
已被那男孩吸收
by the human child.
拯救我們的關鍵就在他的大腦裏
The key to saving our race now lies within his mind.
那就讓我把他的大腦生生給拿出來
Well then, let me strip the very flesh from his body.
你會的，我的徒弟，遲早會的
And you will, my apprentice.
千年以來，我一直夢想能回到那個毀滅的星球
In time. For millenia, I have dreamed of my return
那時我與汽車人還情同手足
to that wretched planet, where I too was once betrayed,
可他們竟然背叛了我
by the Primes I call my brothers.
只有超級戰士才能打敗我
Only a Prime can defeat me,
但是現在只剩一個超級戰士
and now only one remains.
擎天柱，是他在保護那個男孩
Optimus. He protects the boy.
那這個男孩就可以帶我們找到他
Then the boy will lead us to him
這個仇我一定要報是的
- and revenge will be ours.  - Yes.
那男孩跑不掉的，他一直在我們的監視下
The boy will not escape us. We have him in our sights.
但是不補充能量的話，這些新生兒就會死掉
Without more Energon, hatchlings will keep dying.
空間，時間，引力
Space, time, gravity.
謝謝幫我吃完吧
- Thank you.  - Finish that for me.
今天我和你們將要開始一段旅程
We're going on a journey together, you and I, today.
你們正值青春年少，難怪精力過剩
All you, eager nubile young minds on the very cusp of adulthood.
我是你們的夥伴
And I shall be your consort, your guide,
是嚮導，是靈魂伴侶，我能發掘你們的陰暗面
your chaperone, into the heart of darkness.
歡迎聽我的天文課
Welcome to Astronomy 101.
我們對星星的瞭解有多少？
For what do we know about the stars?
處女…處女座
Virgo... the virgin.
獵戶座，也就是射手座
Orion, the great hunter.
可它們沒有閃耀的鑽石
These are no mere twinkling diamonds
供純情少女們日思夜想
for lovely maidens to wish upon.
它們產生的能量規模大的驚人
No, they are diamond, filled with a throbbing,
隨時要噴薄爆發出能量
savage and hemped-up energy.
來看看阿爾伯特·愛因斯坦
Behold the work of Albert Einstein,
那位曾和我一樣的老教授的理論
a professor once, like moi,
- 能量等於質量乘以…
- 你在幹什麼？
- energy, in its mass temp...  - What are you doing?
把手放下，把手放下
Put your hand down, put your hand down.
年輕人，我的課
Young man, there are no questions
到課堂高潮的時候再提問
until I've reached the climax of my lecture.
我看完了你的書，只有一個問題
I've just finished your book. There's only one problem.
愛因斯坦錯了
Einstein's wrong.
一維空間中能量是等於…
Energy doesn't go mass times velocity light square
質量乘以速度的平方，那其它十七維空間呢
in this dimension. What about the other 17
沒人討論這些？
while we're impossible to give 17?
舉例來說：
A clear example:
如果將能量晶體分解
並假定一個常量的衰減速率
通過反射那些領導者反射的信號
就能為交互空間能量發生…
得出一個公式
質量和光速不可能如此解釋…
大家都說說，沒有人同意我嗎…
Come on, guys, I can't be the only one in class...
小伙子，你不能當著系主任的面羞辱我
Young man, I will not be punked in front of the dean.
聽好，這裏我說了算，知道嗎？
No, this is my universe here. Do you understand?
我就是一切，我就是神靈
I am the Alpha and the Omega.
立刻給我出去是，先生
- Get out of my class.  - Yes, sir.
各位，還有誰打算當堂精神崩潰？
Any one else care to have some sort of mental breakdown?
嗨，大骨頭，嗨！
Hi, Bones. Hi!
嗨！哦，好，真是個乖孩子
Hi! Oh yes, that's a good boy.
哦，你今天真乖，太乖了
Oh, what a good boy, you are.
嘿，大骨頭
Hey, Bones.
你餓嗎？
You hungry?
快吃吧
Here you go.
好，薩姆爾喂？米卡拉
- Yes, Samuel.  - Hello? Mikaela.
第一次視頻約會你就放我鴿子
I can't believe you're gonna stand me up on our first web chat date.
出狀況了，知道嗎？
Something just happened to me, okay?
- 怎麼，碰到美女啦？
- 不，不，不…
- Wait, you finally hit puberty?  - No, no, no,
別開玩笑，說真的
Stop laughing. This is serious.
好啦，記得我提到過
Okay, remember I was telling you about
我曾曾曾祖父嗎，阿奇巴德·維基？
my great-great-grandfather, Archibald Witwicky?
記得嗎？
Do you remember?
看著點，你走哪兒去了！
Watch where you're supposed to go!
好的，我當時不是說嗎，好…
Okay, remember I was telling you about, okay...
你不能停下嗎…看著點！別踩著！
Can you stop... Watch the foot! Watch your foot!
好…曾曾曾祖父去了北極，對吧？
Mikaela, okay, my great-great-grandfather went to this Arctic mission, right?
他看到了威震天，威震天電了他
And he saw Megatron, Megatron zapped him
他就開始看到些瘋狂符號，對吧
and he started seeing these crazy symbols, okay.
現在我也看到了，對不起
Well, now I'm seeing them too. Excuse me.
我用32.6秒看完903頁天文學課本
I just wrote a 903-page Astronomy book at 32.6 seconds
我在課堂上精神失常得一塌糊塗
and had a meltdown in the middle of my class.
我看到符號了自從我…
I am seeing symbols ever since I...
- 自從什麼？
- 自從接觸方塊碎片
- Since what?  - Ever since I touched the Cube sliver.
你帶著嗎？
Do you have it?
沒，我放在店裏保險箱裏呢？它很安全
No, how about it's in the shop safe? It's fine.
米卡拉，別碰它，好嗎？別碰它
Mi... Mikaela, do not touch it, okay? Don't touch it.
我不會碰它
I'm not gonna touch it,
山姆，它很好。鎖著呢，沒人知道位置
Sam, it's fine. It's locked away, no one knows where it is.
但我知道
But I do.
你性感，但你很笨
You're hot, but you're ain't too bright.
開工了
There we go.
哦，真他媽可惡！
Oh, big son of a bitch!
看什麼看，呆瓜？
What are you looking at, Slobberpuss?
啊，怎麼…
Ah, what the...
這地方簡直太可怕了
This is a fricking House of Horrors.
等等，就快找到了
Hold on.
你就這麼點能耐嗎，嗯？
Is that the best you got, huh?
你就這麼點能耐嗎？
Is that the best you can do?
你想幹什麼，小畜生？
What are you doing here, you little freak?
哦，那是我的眼睛，瘋女人！
Ow, that's my eye, you crazy bitch!
還不快交代？
You gotta talk now?
我…墮落金剛叫我找方塊裏的真諦
I... I seek knowledge of the Cube. The Fallen demands me.
什麼真諦？
What knowledge?
你有碎片，我需要它，把它給我，給我碎片
You got the shot, I need the shot, give me the shot, I need the shot.
把它給我，他們會宰了我的
Give me the shot, they're gonna whack me,
我拿不到碎片他們會殺了我
I'm gonna be dead without that shot.
輕點，美女小戰士，我只是替人賣命的小角色
Easy Warrior Goddess, I'm just a little salvage scrap drone.
那就做你的噩夢吧
Then I'm your worst nightmare.
嘿，嘿！
Hey, hey!
那是什麼東西？回頭再說
- What the hell was that?  - I'll tell you later,
電話裏不方便，知道嗎？
just not on open phone line, okay?
我現在就去機場，今天下午就能到了
I'm gonna get on a plane right now. I'll be there later this afternoon.
小心點，山姆
Just be careful, Sam.
今天有沒有陌生人讓你帶可疑物品？
And have any stranger giving you anything suspicious to carry on today?
對，一個大盒子！
Yeah, a large box!
沒有很好
- No.  - Good.
符號，那些符號
少校，汽車人發來求救信號
Major, incoming SOS from Autobots.
多個霸天虎開始行動
Multiple Decepticon contacts in motion.
正在接近美國東部，長官
Vicinity eastern United States, sir.
哈斯文，他們有多少？
Hansvin, how many?
還不清楚，長官
Unclear, sir.
那快點弄清楚
Well, get clear.
汽車人出動了，他們分成兩個小分隊，長官
Autobots on the move. Splitting them into two teams, sir.
它們不回應呼叫，在向紐約和費城開進
Unarching their course, somewhere heading to New York and Philadelphia.
好的，全副武裝！二十分鐘後起飛！
Full weapons deployment. Wheels up in 20 minutes!
這裏是57次航班，歡迎來到費城
Flight Chairman throughout West Beverly Hills.
愛麗絲，親愛的，來份超大比薩怎麼樣？
M'amor (my lover), can I interest you in Mayteam Zookeeper's Special?
奶酪加大三倍，每種肉都有
Extra large supertees with every known animal as a topping.
這肉餅直徑有18英吋
Basic lengths. Only 18 inches of meat.
哦，你要是素食者那就算了，好吧，沒事了，我也是
Oh, so you're a vegetarian. Alright, it's cool. I am too.
山姆在嗎？
Is Sam home?
山姆…死了吧，不清楚啊？
Sam... I think he died but, why don't we check?
到了嘿
- Here we are.  - Hey.
你有沒有過腦子裏總是放同一首歌？
Have you had a song stuck in yours?
很難聽，但你卻忍不住
It's like the worst song ever, but you can't help
一直哼著，就這樣，來回放
whistle it or sing it. It's like, repeats itself,
來回放，來回放，來回放，來回放
repeats itself, repeats itself, repeats itself, repeats itself,
來回放…貓咪日曆，貓咪日曆
repeats itself... Kitten calendar, kitten calendar,
貓咪日曆，貓咪日曆兄弟
- kitten calendar, kitten calendar,  - Dude,
貓咪日曆，貓咪日曆怎麼啦
- kitten calendar, kitten calendar,  - What the F?
我知道你要崩潰，別崩潰，別崩潰
I know you're freaking out. Don't freak out, don't freak out.
可以補救，我腦子裏的迷和代碼都寫在牆上呢
Easy fix. Puzzle, code, in my head. Now it's on the walls.
都寫在牆上呢，多棒啊
Everything is good.
這部分…
This is the part that...
好的，說到哪兒了？
Okay, what were you saying?
愛麗絲，對不起把你嚇著了，我們走
Alice, I'm horrified you had to see this. Let's go.
出去什麼？
- Get out.  - What?
等等，等等…我…我能旁聽嗎？
Wait, wait, wait. C-Can I just sit and watch?
我…我不說話，我吃比薩
I-I'll eat my pizza quietly.
山姆，我知道你有非同常人之處
Sam, I knew there were something special about you.
是嗎？
Really?
你我心裏都很清楚
And I know you know what happens
我們同處一室會發生什麼…
when two people in the room get together...
無限驚喜…在床上
they're genuinely amazing... in bed.
謝謝你不客氣
- Thank you.  - No problem.
好吧，等等，注意，別越軌
Alright, listen, hold on. Boundaries. Flight on the plane.
好吧，我很怕癢
Okay, I'm very ticklish.
- 我們都有需要，山姆，放鬆！
- 怎麼了？
- You have the need, Sam. Relax!  - Why?
哦，天啊！
Oh, jeez!
呃…聊聊金融危機吧？挺刺激，對吧？
Uh, what about this economy? It's crazy, isn't it?
你也太主動了放鬆就好
- You are very aggressive.  - Just relax.
要土耳其麵包嗎？
You want some jerky meatloaf?
山姆？
Sam?
米卡拉
Mikaela.
你女朋友？
Is that your girlfriend?
前女友
Ex.
米卡拉，等等…我可以解釋一切…
Mikaela, wait... I can explain every...
山姆，你的床友，愛麗絲
Sam, your bed-buddy, Alice.
什麼…
What...
來了！是女外星人
- It's coming!  - This is an alien robot.
你得走，快跑真的嗎？
- You gotta move. Just run.  - They're real?
哦，我的天，難以置信，我夢裏還跟她親熱來著
Oh my God, I can't believe I once had sex with her in my dream.
你可真是想念我啊，山姆
I can tell that you really missed me a lot, Sam.
聽著，這不是我的錯，好吧？
Look, it's not my fault, okay?
聽著，聽著，我是受害人
Listen, listen. I'm a victim.
哦，你是受害人？受什麼害？
Oh, you were a victim? Of what?
受什麼害？一個８０磅的女孩…
- Of what? A little 80-pound girl...  - Of...Of...
脖子就像被頭野母牛騷擾一樣
It's like getting humped in the neck by a mountain ox.
你不該把舌頭放她嘴裏
You didn't have to put your tongue in her mouth.
我沒有你有
- I didn't.  - You did.
聽著，是她把五尺長舌頭伸進我胃裏了
Look, you ever had your stomach tounged by a mountain ox with a 5-foot tong?
我不覺得這好玩，好了，米卡拉
It's not fun for me, okay, Mikaela.
而且聞起來像…柴油，柴油味滿嘴都是
And it smelled like... like diesel. Like a diesel he dinged to it.
你真是個小女孩
You're such a little girl.
我們倆先沉默十秒鐘，現在
You have ten seconds of silence, right now.
十秒內不和你說話
I'm not talking to you for ten seconds.
不，你還敢叫我閉嘴，你知道嗎？
No, you can't give me the silence. You know what?
我十秒內不和你說話，還剩三秒
I'm not talking to you for ten seconds. You have three seconds left.
聽著，什麼？你想不說可以不說
You know, what? You can give me the silence you want,
但別不讓我說話…
all you want but you can't give me the talking...
你…你想說什麼？
W-What were you gonna say?
剛才你爽了吧…
I hope you had a lot of fun because this...
咱們一刀兩斷！
This is over!
她把髒舌頭伸你嘴裏了？
Did she finally led you to orbits?
進去了？她真做了，真進去了？
You threw a broom? She did it, she went in it?
那你肚子裏就會有小外星人了，他們可能正在長大，兄弟
...gestating in that inside of you. You're going right now, bro.
你應該趕緊吐出來，馬上吐，馬上吐
You need to vomit right now. Yak it, yak it.
馬上！你是哪位？
- Right now!  - Who are you?
我是唯一誰都能吐槽的人，懂嗎？
I am the only one who everybody can spit, okay?
我可是關鍵
I'm the key to this.
外星人他們找來是因為我的網站
Aliens; they want me because of my site.
快跑！
Run!
米奇拉！
Mikaela!
小心，我們進去
Watch out. We get in.
是炸彈！
It's a bomb!
拿上箱子
We gotta get that box.
進來
This way.
嘿，讓我出去，讓我出去！
Hey, let me out, let me out!
天啊，你還會這麼點火？
Oh my God, you know to hot-wire a car?
真性感快開，快開，快開
- That's so hot.  - Drive, drive, drive.
她來了，她來了！
She went there, she went there!
等…等！
W-wait!
他們會…
They can....
切，切，切
Cut, cut, cut.
哦，上帝！
Oh God!
親這個吧，賤貨
Kiss this, bitch.
開，開，開，開，開，開
Drive, drive, drive, drive, drive, drive.
好，發生什麼事了，好吧
Okay, so what else's going right now, alright,
這些外星人怎麼回事？
did you guys just mess with the minor details?
剛才你看到的，還算客氣的
Thing you saw back there. That was a little babe.
哇啊！我的天哪！我的天哪！
Whoa! Oh my God! Oh my God!
山姆！
Sam!
山姆！抓住了！
- Sam!  - Hold on!
抓住
Hold on.
山姆！
Sam!
我不想死！我們完蛋了！哦，我的天！
I don't want to die! We're going to die! Oh my God!
哦，老天！哦，天！
Oh, Jesus! Oh, jeez!
過來，小子
Come here, boy.
近點
Closer.
好的
Okay.
- 你記得我，對吧？
- 我照你說的做，好嗎？
- You remember me, don't you?  - I did what you said, okay?
別傷害我們閉嘴！
- Just don't hurt us.  - Shut up!
山姆！
Sam!
挖你的肉感覺真不錯
It feels good to grab your first.
我會讓你慢慢痛苦地死
I am going to kill you, slowly, painfully.
但首先我們有些細緻的工作要做
But first, we have some delicate work to do.
我怎麼能把你的胳膊掰斷
I could snap your ribs off.
醫生，來檢查一下這個外星物種
Doctor, examine this alien specimen.
看夠你的臉了
Sick of your face now.
我是醫生！你看著我
我問什麼，你答什麼
你是想舒服還是想難受？
去那邊
Go that way.
討厭的蟲…
A wormy that's crabby...
- 哦，就是這個
- 這是我腦子裏的
- Oh, there they are.  - That's what I'm seeing in my head.
這些符號能指引我們找到能量源
These symbols can lead us to the Energon source.
我們得把他大腦取出來！放到這桌上，快！
We must tear the brain!
大腦？你們要我大腦幹什麼？
Brain? What does he mean by my brain?
哦…你腦子裏有點東西
Well, you have something on your mind.
- 是我需要的
- 等等，我知道你生氣
- Something I need.  - Hold on. I know you're pissed.
我知道你生氣
I know you're pissed.
你生氣是因為我想殺你，這是誤會
Because I tried to kill you and it's completely understandable.
有人想殺我的話，我也會鬱悶的
Somebody tried to kill me, I'd be upset too.
我認為完全有機會
I think that we have an opportunity here
重新開始…改善我們的關係
to start a new and... and develop our relationship,
然後…然後看看它會把我們帶向哪兒，好嗎？
and... and, see where it leads us, okay?
你就把醫生叫來
So you just call doctor inspection,
5秒鐘後我會讓你說
I'll let you talk in five seconds.
等等…
W-Wait...
走，走
Go, go.
走，走，走
Go, go, go.
山姆！
Sam!
走，走，走，走！
Go, go, go, go!
他來了！
Here he comes!
藏起來，山姆！藏起來
Hide, Sam! Hide.
懦夫
Weak.
很小聲
Puny.
大點聲
Voiced-up.
廢物，敗類
Junkyard drone.
霸天虎！
Decepticons!
過來，小子
Come here, boy.
還有一個能量源隱藏在這個星球上
There is another source of Energon hidden on this planet.
這孩子可以帶我們找到它
The boy can lead us to it.
擎天柱！
Optimus!
難道我們種族的未來還不如一個人類的生命重要嗎？
Is the future of our race not worth a single human life?
擎天柱，起來！
Op, get up!
你殺人成癮了
You'll never stop at one.
我絕不會放過你們
I'll take you all alive.
山姆，你在哪兒？
Sam, where are you?
你太不經打了
You are so weak.
終於，超級領袖都死了
At last, Prime is dead.
山姆，快跑
Sam, run.
汽車人，進攻！
Autobots, attack!
大黃蜂，快帶他們離開這兒
Bumblebee, get them out of here.
這是倫諾克
This is Lennox.
幹得不錯
That went well.
主人，那孩子跟丟了
Lost the boy, Master.
汽車人把信號都隱蔽了
The Autobots must be shielding the signals.
- 連個小小的人類你都幹不掉
- 對不起，不
- I can't even rely on you.  - Sorry. No.
多簡單的昆蟲！
What a simple insect!
七十億之中的…閉嘴
- What insect amongst severed billion...  - Shut up.
大海撈針啊
It could be anywhere.
那就強迫所有的人類來幫我們找
Then we will force them to find him for us.
該讓全世界知道我們的存在了
It's time for the world to know of our presence.
不再遮遮掩掩，不再手下留情！
No more disguises, no mercy!
該輪到我的主人出場了
Time has come for my master's arrival.
霸天虎，出發
Decepticons, mobilise.
時候到了
It is time.
哦，單身就這點好！
Oh, that single's good!
說法語真讓人興奮
Speaking French is so exciting.
哦，我的天，這是誰？
Oh God, who is this?
「你好」…我是說…下午好！
Hello... I mean, uh, bon...bonswa(good afternoon)!
什麼？你誰呀？
What? Who is this?
哦，想氣死我呀
Oh, for Pete's sakes.
我可不欣賞你在電話裏瞎喘氣
I'm not impressed with your perverted mouth breathing.
（紐約市）
New York City
哦，天哪
Oh, jeez.
你在侵犯我的私人空間，小心我揍你
You are invading my space. I'm gonna have to drop you.
走開行嗎？
Would you get out of here?
差點把我嚇死
Might freak me out.
我想吃點新菜
We're gonna try new things.
看上去像加拿大天鵝糞
Looks like Candian goosepoop.
你真噁心
It's nasty.
（美國第二艦隊，北大西洋）
不錯，１- ２
- ５
That's fine, 1-2-5.
那是什麼？出什麼事了？
我來復仇了
Revenge is mine.
（五角大樓 - 華盛頓特區）
航空母艦不會無故下沉
…不知道是意外還是恐怖襲擊，甚至有更糟的可能
...port accident for a terrorist attack, or worse.
不是，空防方面確認了
Negative. NORAD confirmed
投射物來自大氣層外
project came from beyond our atmosphere
時速高達三萬節
inbound at 30, 000 knot.
地球上的人類
Citizens of the human hive,
你們的領導者掩蓋了事實
your leaders have withheld the truth.
在宇宙中你們並不孤單
You are not alone in this universe.
我們藏在你們身邊躲著…
We have lived among you, hidden...
但今後不會了
but no more.
你們都看到了
As you've seen,
我們能隨意摧毀你們的城市
we can destroy your cities at will.
除非你們交出這個男孩
Unless you turn over this boy.
你們膽敢反抗
If you resist us,
我們必將摧毀整個世界，你們知道的
we will destroy the world, as you know it.
德國政府表示，這段講話是
What we're hearing from the German government is that
通過非法入侵衛星得以播出的，軍方人士透露
the world broadcast is a satellite hacking. - The military has just told us
（巢穴部隊 - 新澤西州）
- NEST Team, New Jersey
安全防禦級別已升至三級
they have assumed Condition Delta,
是9.11事件以來的最高級別
which is the highest level we've been at since 9/11.
總統已飛抵…
President Obama is being flown to a bunker,
美國中部的某指揮中心
somewhere in the middle of the United States.
以應對此次全球同一時間…
in the phase of the worst simultaneous attacks ever
遭受的襲擊
around the globe.
美國羅斯福號航空母艦在美國東海岸沉沒
The aircraft carrier, USS Roosevelt, goes down off the East Coast
沒有生還者
all hands lost.
世界範圍內的傷亡人數大約在七千人左右
Worldwide casualties are in the neighbourhood of 7,000,
但數字仍在上升
but that number could implode.
尚無法確定
It's still too early to tell.
我們想問敵人是誰，為什麼攻擊
What we need to ask now, is who and why.
聯邦調查局仍在尋找這個男孩-山姆·維基
The FBI is still trying to locate the boy, Sam Witwicky.
（聯邦調查局新聞發佈會）
他們應該知道整個襲擊的事情
Within deep, they have information about this.
FBI、CIA、國際刑警組織
The FBI, CIA and Interpol
都在尋求各國司法部門的相關協助
are all seeking the cooperation of worldwide law enforcements.
嘿，哥們，聽聽這個…
Hey bro, you need to listen to this, man.
- 你得看看
- 隻要他們有交通攝像頭
- You gotta check this out.  - Once they have a traffic camera
- 拍到一張山姆·維基的照片
- 我被拍到了，哥們
- spotting a Sam Witwicky.  - They have a picture of me, man.
我們死定了，兄弟，聯邦調查局，中情局現在正在通緝我們
We're dead, bro. FBI, CIA, we're wanted fugitives now.
你先看一眼，哥們
I just need you to focus just one minute, man.
整個事件的性質現在升級了，對吧
This thing is blowing to a whole another level, alright.
你知道…動一下這東西
- You know one thing...  - Remove this thing.
他們能跟蹤我們，看到嗎？
They can track us. Do you see this?
什麼？
What?
他們能跟蹤我們？
They can track us?
用衛星跟蹤我們？
Like satellite-track us?
喔…好吧，我都不是你們一夥的
Whoa, whoa, whoa, okay, I'm not even with you guys.
實際上，我是人質，這是綁架，我才不會…
Technically, I'm like a hostage. This is kidnapping. Enough...
嘿，裏奧！
Yo, Leo!
你想讓我得心臟病，肯定的
This thing's gonna give me a heart attack, I swear.
那是因為你膽子太小
That's 'cause you was a wuss.
是你們逼我上車的吧？
You did force me into the car, right?
所以…哦，我想你是害怕了
- So...  - Oh, I think you scared.
嘿，擋泥板
Hey, Mudflap.
咱們該拿他怎麼辦？
What are we going to do with this shrimp taco?
一槍幹掉，扔後備箱裏
Just pop a cap in his ass, throw him in the trunk
沒人知道，明白我意思嗎？
and nobody gonna know nothing, y'know I mean?
等等，我的車…碰碰車
- Wait, now my trunk...  - Yo, bumper cars,
聽我說，我可全聽見了，知道嗎？
Check it out. I'm hearing you, okay?
我就在這兒，我能聽到你們的話
I'm right here and I can hear you.
你們不會開槍，也不會毀屍滅跡，好吧？
No one's popping any caps in any asses, okay?
今天我真倒霉
I've had a hell of a day.
看你連頭髮都弄不好？
Why don't you get a haircut with your bitch ass?
找你的山姆去吧
Go whine to your boyfriend.
聽著，山姆，我知道該做什麼
Listen Sam, I know what I'm gonna do, man.
聽著，我會去找政府
Look, I'm just going to go to the authorities
告訴他們真相，我跟這一切無關
and tell them the truth. Like I had nothing to do with this,
我是個同夥嘿，嘿！
- I'm an accomplice.  - Hey, hey!
是你自願的，不是嗎？因為這就是真相
You wanted this, right? You wanted the real deal?
醒醒吧！你脫不了干係
'Cause that's what this is. Wake up! You're in the middle of it.
想走就走，沒人攔著你
You wanna run, go ahead, no one's stopping you.
別再抱怨了
Stop complaining.
這是什麼意思？
What is the meaning of this?
你敢拿槍對著我？
You dare point your gun at me?
你想跟我打嗎？我要把你撕成碎片！
You want a piece of me? I will tear you apart!
放下武器！放下武器！
Drop your weapons! Drop your weapons!
- 叫他們放下槍
- 叫汽車人先放
- Tell them to lower the weapons.  - Tell them first.
讓他們放下武器！
Tell them to lower the weapons!
少校，我也無能為力
Major, there's nothing I can do.
你自己和他說吧
Talk to him.
你的隊伍解散了，少校
US teams deactivated, Major.
停止對霸天虎的一切對抗行為
You are decease anti-Decepticon operations,
返回迭戈·加西亞基地。還有別的指示嗎？
and return to Diego Garcia. Any further orders?
我們直接聽從墨邵爾將軍的命令
No. We take our orders direct from Chairman Morshower.
好吧，我會見你的領導和參謀長
Well, I'll see your chairman and the Joint Chiefs of Staff
我有總統的手令，你別無選擇
but I will raise you a President of the United States.
你現在必須聽我的命令
I have operational command now.
外星人跑到我們星球復仇
An alien blood feud has been brought to our shores
卻要我們的戰士遭殃
for which our soldiers are paying the price.
真相大白了，我們也參戰了
The secret is out. This is our war now.
我們會再次贏得勝利
And we will win it as we always have,
靠的是全面的軍事策略
with a coordinated military strategy.
這個蠢貨完全想歪了
This fool is terribly misinformed.
這些戰士你全都需要
You're gonna get every assets that you've got.
我需要的是作戰計劃
What we need is to draw our battle plans.
盡一切可能的外交解決途徑
What we explore every possible, diplomatic solution.
比如什麼：交出那個孩子嗎？
Like what: Handing over the kid?
這也不是沒有可能
All options are being considered.
畢竟霸天虎都跟來了
Whatever the Decepticons are after,
這只是個開始
this is just the start.
等等，絕不能和他們談判
Wait, there is no negotiating with them.
你被解職了
I'm ordering you to stand down.
不再需要這個了
You won't be needing this any more.
帶著你的寶貝們
Get your assets back to base.
和那堆廢銅爛鐵回基地去
Take that scrap metal back to Diego Garcia.
我們走
Let's go.
我真的不喜歡那哥們
I really don't like that dude.
他是個瘋子
He's a asshole.
汽車人，請到機庫報到
Autobots, report to hangar for transport.
鐵皮，我們該離開這個星球
Ironhide, we should leave this planet.
但擎天柱並不希望這樣
That's not what Optimus would want.
你已經盡力了
There's nothing that you could have done.
你還好嗎？還好
- You okay?  - Yeah.
夥計，我能理解，如果你恨我
Bee, if you hate me, I understand.
我弄砸了
I messed up.
對不起
I'm sorry.
年輕人，你是…
- Young fella, you are...
…我這輩子最在意的人
- ...person I care about most in my life.
只要你需要我…我不會離你很遠的
- If there's anything you need...  - I won't be far away.
他是因為我才死的
He's dead because of me.
他保護了我，可他卻死了
He came in to protect me instead.
有些事情你無法改變
There's some things you just can't change.
這樣他的犧牲…
So this sacrifice was...
才不會失去意義！
will not have been in vain, hallelujah!
這一回我決不退縮
We make it right when we turn myself in.
但我們，我們要團結在一起
But we, we've got to stick together.
你不會來真的吧？
You're not gonna do that.
是的，我會的
Yes, I am.
不然我們的努力全白費了
Everything we worked for will be wiped out.
一天內
In one day.
你們倆嗯？
- You two.  - Huh?
嘿，認得嗎？
Hey, you know the glyphs?
這些是我腦子裏的符號
The symbols that have been rattling around in my head.
那是古老符號，嘿
That's old school, yo.
應該是…古塞伯坦語
That's like... That's Cybertonian.
哦，這肯定有什麼重要的含義
Oh, that's some serious stuff in there.
他們肯定有什麼意思，比如信息…
They gotta mean something, like a message...
或者，也可能是…是地圖！
or, like a... like a map!
能找到能量源的地圖
Like a map to an Energon source.
能讀懂嗎？
Can you read this?
讀？不會你看到嗎？
- Read? Nah.  - You see that?
不，我們…我們不怎麼會讀
No, we... we don't really do much reading.
不太會那你們如果不懂
- Not so much.  - Well if you can't read it,
那就找懂的人去
we gotta find somebody who can.
哦，看，膽小鬼又回來了
Oh, look, who came stashing and back.
看他髮型多搞笑呀，那兒，看
Hair grown like a chip, there, look it.
我剛才是被嚇壞了，行了吧？
I had a bit of a mild panic attack earlier, alright?
那是因為你跟女人似的
That's 'cause you're a pussy.
我跟你們一路過來
I think I'm allowed that considering what I've been through
而且…聽說有問題
and... I heard you have a problem.
我想我能找人幫忙
I think I know someone who can help.
誰？機器戰士網站
- Who?  - Robo-Warrior.
這人，機器戰士…
This guy, Robo-Warrior...
一切跟外星人有關的，他都知道
Everything about anything alien, he's supposed to know.
有一次我黑他網站時
One time we hacked this site
好像，看見過…這種汽車外星人的符號之類的
and maybe, I saw some of your, uh... alien drawings or whatever.
就這兒了
This is it.
嗯，便利店，很好的掩護所
Yep, deli. Good front.
好，稍等。我說進來再進來，好嗎？
Alright, wait here. I'll give you the go/no go, alright?
42號桌點的香腸，猶太餡餅
Number 42, we got your... Right here...
雞肉蕎麥粥
三角肉包套餐好了…給…
只收現金，下一位？
Cash only. Who's next?
我說過鮭魚先用鹽水泡再煙熏
I told you put the salmon in the salt and then smoke.
媽，你想折磨死我啊？
Ma, you want me to cut my handle off or what?
你要了塊非常差勁的魚
- You order a terrible piece of fishing.
我的刀功很棒，就跟忍者一樣
- I'm like a ninja, with a blade.
給我閃開！
Get out of here!
嘿，山姆！規矩點，嗯？
Hey, Sam! Watch your reach, huh?
拿個號，小伙子
Take a number, young man.
機器戰士
Robo-Warrior.
認識他嗎？
Know him?
沒聽說過
I never heard of him.
聽說過「真實的世界.com」吧？
You never heard of TheRealEffingDeal.com?
是那個超級白癡的博客網站
You must be talking about that amateur blog operation
它的防火牆形同虛設
with GameBoy level security.
機器戰士
Robo-Warrior.
就是他，就是他！就是這傢伙
It's him. It's him! That's the guy right there.
就是他
That's him.
不是吧
No.
開玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
各位，本店打烊了，全部出去！
Alright, meat store's closed. Everybody out!
出去，現在！
Go, right now!
等下，你認識這個人嗎？
Wait a minute, you know this guy?
我們是老相識了老相識
- We're old friends.  - Whoa, friend,
就因為你，第七區撤消了編製
you are the case that shut down Sector 7.
全員遣散回老家
Got the tie-bash disbandment,
沒有風光的工作，沒有退休金，一無所有
no more security clearance, no retirement, no nothing.
全都因為你和你相好的女少年犯
All 'cause of you, and your little criminal girlfriend.
看看她，辣妹一個
Look at her now, so mature.
白癡，鱒魚在哪兒？
Moron, where's the wifresh?
別讓我碰到那些肉
Don't catch me with the thing.
亞科夫！幹嘛？
- Yakov!  - What?
再傻站著年終獎金取消
You don't get Christmas bonus just standing around.
你還想攢錢鑲新牙嗎？
You want those new teeth you saw in SkyMall?
當然了那去幫幫她
- It's my dream.  - Help around.
- 你和媽媽一起住嗎？
- 媽媽和我住
- You live with your momma?  - No, my momma lives with me,
這是兩回事
it's a big difference.
電視上全是你的照片，外星仔
They got your face all over the news, alien boy.
- 好，我知道
- 那威震天還活著啊？
- Yeah, I know.  - And NBE-1, still kicking, huh?
這是怎麼回事？
How did that happen?
別回答，我不知道你的秘密
Don't answer. I don't know what you're hiding,
但也不想有任何瓜葛
but I don't want anything to do with it
就此分手，只當你沒見過我，我還要做事，趕緊消失
so, goodbye, you never saw me. I got bagels to schmidt.
給我五秒鐘時間
Well, give me 5 seconds.
聽著，等等，我要你幫忙
Look, hold on, I need your help.
真的，你要我幫忙？
Really, you need my help?
我要…
I need...
好吧，我差點掉了腦袋，明白嗎？
Look, I am slowly losing my mind, okay?
那機器人醫生把設備
I had a little Crabbot, placed the device
植入我大腦軟組織
deep into the soft tissues of my brain,
像家庭影院一樣
and started projecting little alien symbols
放映出外星語符號
like a whole freaking movie
而且我還是個逃犯
and on top of that, I'm a wanted fugitive.
你能理解嗎？
So you think you got it rough?
你腦子裏的圖像被投射出來？
You said it projected images of your brain?
對
Right.
冷凍室，快！
Meat locker, now!
速凍肉真噁心
- Dead pigs.  - Yuck.
你們將看到的是最高機密
What you're about to see is top secret.
千萬別告訴我媽
Do not tell my mother.
速凍肉，會得病的
Dead pigs, swine flu.
不好現在你知道了
- Not good.  - Now you know.
下次吃肉的時候
Next time, you eat a goat or a pig.
想想背後的故事
There's a story behind this.
對，有故事
Yeah, there's a story.
…你說你相信有外星人？
...you're saying you believe in aliens?
好的，資料，資料
Okay, files, files.
我們談的是符號
We're talking about symbols.
嘿！還有放射性，別碰
Hey! Still radioactive. Hands off.
好了，小腦瓜
Okay, Cube-brain.
你看到的是這些符號嗎？
Any of these look like the symbols you saw?
你哪兒弄的？
Where did you get these?
我被解雇之前
Before I got fired.
從第七區弄到的獨家資料…
I coached S-7's scrawny, drooly...
歷時七十五年的外星人研究，指出了一個不容迴避的事實：
75 years of alien research which points to one inescapable fact:
變形金剛，很久以前就來過地球
The Transformers; they've been here a long, long time.
要證據嗎？
How do I know?
考古學家在世界各地的名勝古跡中
Archaeologists found these unexplained markings
發現了這些標記
and ancient runes all over the world.
中國、埃及、希臘
China, Egypt, Greece.
1932年拍的
Shot at 1932.
這些符號見過嗎？
These the symbols you're seeing in your head?
對一模一樣，是吧？
- Yeah.  - Same ones over here, right?
那麼，告訴我，誰會留下一樣的圖案呢？
So, tell me, how did they end up all drawing the same thing?
外星人
Aliens.
而且我覺得有些人就沒離開過
And I think some of them stayed.
看看這個
Check this out.
黑刀的計劃
Project Black Knife.
偽裝的機器人一直潛伏在地球
Robots, in disguise. Hiding here.
一直以來
All along.
我們在全國範圍內均檢測到放射性物質
We detected radioactive signatures all across the country.
我甚至下跪求第七區對此調查
I pleaded on my knees with S-7 to investigate it
但他們說讀數少得可以忽略
but they said the readings were infantesimal.
還說我是在做夢！
That I was obsessed!
我，你能相信嗎？
Me, can you imagine that?
威震天說這兒還有個能量源
Megatron said that there was another Energon source here.
地球上？地球上另一個能量源？
- On Earth? On another source?  - On Earth.
好的，還有個能量源
Okay, and that these symbols,
而且我這裏的符號地圖能夠指路
the maps in my head would lead him there.
你和汽車人說了嗎？
Should you talk to your Autobot friends?
沒有，沒有…他們是後來的
No, no, no, the source is before.
不管能量源是什麼，他們比汽車人早
Whatever the Energon source is, it predates them. It's before them.
所以比他們更早對
- So it comes before that.  - Correct.
那麼，報告…
Well then, report...
除非問一問霸天虎
Unless we can talk to a Decepticon.
我是說，你不用跟它客氣…
I mean, I'm not on speed terms or whatever...
其實，我是
Actually, I am.
讓我出去！
Let me out!
讓它吃點苦頭打開
- It could be a little bit sad.  - Open it.
我找一幫霸天虎踹死你！
I'm gonna so many Decepticons on your butt!
老實點
Behave.
這也是霸天虎？對
- What is it, a Decepticon?  - Yeah.
你能訓練他嗎？我試試
- Can you train him?  - Tried to.
我花了畢生的精力尋找外星人
I spent my whole adult life, coming a plan of aliens.
- 你非常憤怒…
- 而你帶個外星人
- You're very furious...  - And you're carrying it around
卻像遛狗一樣
what are you supposed to make a little chihuahua.
想打架嗎，你這個卷毛？
Wanna throw it down, you pubic fro-head?
對不起，抱歉弄壞你的眼睛
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry about your eye.
你知道，如果你能老實點
You know, but if you're a good boy,
我就不弄瞎另一隻了，好嗎？
then I'm not gonna torch your other eye.
我不再折磨你
Okay? I'm not gonna torch it.
告訴我這些符號是什麼
Just tell me what these symbols are.
求你了
Please.
好吧
Okay.
哦，我知道。這是超級領袖的語言
Oh, I know that. That's the language of the Primes.
我讀不了，但是這些傢伙…
I don't read it, but uh, these guys...
你在哪兒找到的照片？
Where the frick did you find photos of these guys?
就是他們嗎？對
- Is this them?  - Yeah.
首批探險者，夥計，資格最老的
Sakers, pal. Oldest of the old.
哦，他們幾千年前
Oh, they've been here for thousands of years,
就到這裏找東西
looking for something.
不知是什麼，也沒有人告訴我
I don't know what, nobody tells me nothing.
哦，他們可以翻譯這些符號
Oh, they'll translate those symbols for ya.
我知道他們在哪兒
And I know where to find them.
快說吧
Show us.
最近的在華盛頓
Closest one's in Washington.
美國航空航天博物館
Smithsonian Air and Space Museum.
我的夢想國度
Land of dreams in there.
我曾夢想當名宇航員
All I ever want to be was an astronaut.
拿著那是什麼？
- Hold those.  - What is that?
什麼？
What?
我穿上它壯膽
I wear them when I'm in the funk.
傑姆比也是，騙子，這是運動員的裝備
So does Jeamby, Cheater. It's a baseball thing.
好了，對好表，高度警惕，少上廁所
Okay. Once you synchronize, shop-mind and empty bladder
萬一被抓上了法庭，別供出我來
you get caught, demand an attorney and don't ever say my name.
給，吃一片
Here, take one of these pills.
放在舌頭下面
Slip it under your tongue,
這是64E84192用的高濃度巧克力
it's a high-concentrate polymer they put in Oreo cookies.
用它騙測謊儀，屢試不爽
Fools the polygraph, everytime.
好了，我們上路吧
Okay, now let's get this show on the road.
不，聽著，我不能幹這個
Whoa, no, listen. I can't do this.
我不想抓外星人，好嗎？
I'm not some alien bounty hunter, alright?
因為我不想幹這個，守衛有槍
'cause I'm not gonna do this. Guards have guns,
- 我不想死
- 孩子、孩子、孩子…
- I don't want to die.  - Kid, kid, kid, kid, kid, kid.
你要是打退堂鼓，你就死定了
You compromise this mission, you are dead to me.
看著我的眼睛，收緊括約肌
Now look into my eyes, and tighten up that spare tank.
博物館要關門了
The museum is now closing.
哥們，我麻煩了，兄弟
Papa, bad news, bro.
紙用完了，你這兒有嗎？
Ran out of toilet paper, you got any out here?
- 拜託，一定要有…
- 先生，我建議你回去那裏
- Please tell me you...  - Sir, I suggest you get in there.
馬上要閉館了
The museum is closed.
聽著，我也理解你們
Listen man, I understand that,
但你也看到了，這事很重要
but as you can see, this is important.
我要解大手，我會走了，好嗎？
Dumper-dumper. I gotta go, alright?
先生，你可是一個成年裸男，現在還在到處走…
Sir, you are a grown naked man around showing...
- 穿上你的褲子並離開…
- 我哪兒也不去
- Pull your pants up and exit...  - I'm not going anywhere.
你有紙吧，對不，先生？
You got that paper, right, sir?
你應該感到尷尬
You should be embarassed.
這是個對家庭開放的博物館，先生
This a family museum, sir.
這兒怎麼回事？
What is going on here?
你能忍受幾次這樣的瘋子？
How many times can you get tased in the nuts?
那你去把著門，嗯，你知道
So you covered the gates, huh, you know.
你是個業餘的，有水平的外行
You're an amateur man, a rank amateur.
現在有五個警衛，五個警衛
There's now five guards. Five guards.
你拿著這個並離開這裏
You get this stuff and get out of here.
給我一秒鐘
Give me a second.
有人在跟蹤我，好吧
I gotta get the tracker, alright.
會沒事的我有幽閉恐怖癥
- Be good.  - I'm claustrophobic.
看，看，跟著他，跟著他
Look, look. Follow him, follow him.
他知道他要去哪兒
He knows where he's going.
他知道什麼什麼？
- He knows something.  - What?
他知道什麼！
He knows something!
你知道我指的嗎？對
- You got what I got?  - Yeah.
黑鳥
Blackbird.
他來了
There he is.
這人是個奇跡，就像…領導一樣
This guy's a legend, like... like the Chairman of the Board.
對，年輕人，把碎片放上去
Yo, freshman, put the shard.
看看會發生什麼
And watch the magic happen.
哦，壞了，這是霸天虎！
Oh shit, it's a Decepticon!
霸天虎？這是什麼？
- Decepticon?  - What is it?
快躲那邊去！
Find the main tail!
這什麼陵園啊？
What sort of hideous mosalleem is this?
回答我，你們這幫蝦兵蟹將！
快亮身份不然死無葬身之地！
Semi pulls and days, show yourselves!Or suffer my infinite wrath!
等等，你們這些直立行走動物
W-wait, old spinal called based organisms.
閃開！
Bugger!
記住我天火的永恆光輝！
Behold the eternal glory of Jetfire!
啟動遠程系統自控
Prepare for a systems' override.
告訴你，這傢伙還挺新潮
I tell you, this guy did not age well.
- 他也聽不到
- 我命令打開這些門
- He either heard it.  - Command these doors to open.
開火！
Fire!
哦，我說了，開火！
Oh, I said, fire!
蠢貨
Bollocks.
打開它，這些沒用的東西…
Break that, these worthless...
等一下
Wait a second.
我屁股又癢得要命
Itching, wretching, rust in my arse.
哦，這一回博物館會非常生氣
Oh, the museum's gonna be very angry.
非常生氣，我們得上飛機！
Very angry. We gotta catch that plane!
我在執行任務
I'm on a mission.
等等，等等！等一下，等等，等等
- W-wait, wait!  - Wait, wait, wait.
嘿！你們要幹什麼？
- Hey!  - What do you want?
聽著，我們只想談談！
Look, we just want to talk!
我沒時間談，我在執行任務！
I've no time to talk, I'm on a mission!
我這樣的人見人怕
I'm a mercenary goon-bringer.
這是哪個星球？地球
- What planet am I on?  - Earth.
地球？真是太難聽了
Earth? Terrible name for a planet,
還不如叫「土球」
might as well call it "dirt".
土的星球
Planet dirt.
告訴我，機器人還在打內戰嗎？
Tell me, is that robot civil war still going on?
誰贏了？霸天虎
- Who's winning?  - The Decepticons.
那…我轉投汽車人那邊了
Well, I changed sides to the Autobots.
什麼意思，「轉投」？
What do you mean, "changed sides"?
這是個選擇
It's a choice.
這是經過激烈思想鬥爭的選擇。消極因素太多
It's intensely personal decision. So much negativity.
光靠仇恨怎麼活啊？
Who wants to live a life filled with hate?
你是說不想再跟著…
Meaning you don't have to work for those
那些霸天虎混了？
miserable, freaking Decepticons?
霸天虎要是勝利了，將毀滅整個宇宙
If they set on their way, they destroy the whole Universe.
我也轉投汽車人了，我也轉投了
I'm changing sides, I'm changing sides,
我的女神雅典娜！
Warrior Goddess!
- 你的小機器人呢？
- 哦，你真可愛
- Who's your little Autobot?  - Oh you cutes.
我叫小威
Name's Wheelie.
來叫我名字，叫我名字！
Say my name, say my name!
它這麼亂來你都能忍？
What are you allowing to happen to your foot just now?
它至少專一，山姆
At least he's faithful, Sam.
好，它不僅是專一，還沒臉沒皮
Yeah, well, he's faithful, and he's nude and he's perverted.
你消停會…行嗎？
Can you just... Can you stop?
- 嘿，你在幹什麼？
- 我不想多囉嗦
- Hey, what are you doing?  - ...I don't wanna argue it.
你在說什麼？
What were you saying?
我在告訴你，我叫天火！
I told you my name was Jetfire!
有些人一大早心情就不好呀？
Wow, someone shit in the bed this morning?
我叫天火！我情緒問題是我媽遺傳的
Pretty stout with my mother.
我的祖先來這已經幾個世紀了
My ancestors have been here for centuries.
我父親他是第一代轉輪！第一代轉輪！
My father, one was a wheel! The first wheel!
- 知道他變形成什麼嗎？
- 不知道
- Do you know what he transformed into?  - No.
什麼也變次了！但是他死得光榮，死得其所…
Nothing! But he did so with honor, dignity and...
我的助推器壞了
My boosters are fried.
我覺得我們應該互相幫助
I thought we could help each other.
你懂的我不懂，我懂的你不懂
You know things I don't know. I know things you don't know.
真的我覺得他什麼都不懂
- I do.  - I don't think he knows anything.
說實話，我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
這些生動的符號
These vivid symbols,
雖說是符號但我都記在我腦子裏
they're symbols but they are in my mind.
看，都在我腦子裏
You see, all this is in my mind.
威震天逼我記下來
And Megatron wants what's in my mind.
他和一個叫墮落金剛的干的
Him and someone called the Fallen.
墮落金剛？我知道他，是他讓我在這兒生銹的
The Fallen? I know him. He left me here to rust.
那個霸天虎
The original Decepticon.
它可不好惹，滿腦子都是毀滅，混亂，危機…
He's terrible to work for. He's always apocalypse, chaos...
他的懷疑，也是我任務的一部分
His suspects, they were a part of my mission
墮落金剛要找，想起來了
the Fall and Search, I remember now.
要找匕首之尖和一把鑰匙
Of a dagger's tip and the key!
慢點，匕首之尖，鑰匙
Slow down. The dagger's tip, the key,
你在說什麼？沒時間說啦
- what are you talking about?  - No time to explain.
抓緊了，大家
Hold on, everybody!
哦，那也沒太糟糕
Well, that wasn't so bad.
我看錯了個星球
I was overseeing the wrong planet.
嘿，太疼了！
Hey, that frickin' hurt!
哦，天哪！
Oh, God!
哦，我的天！你那美麗的臉龐，這會是完美的一刻
Oh, my God! You beautiful face, this will be a perfect moment.
只是你降落在了我的重要部位上
Except you landed on my testicles.
拜託你下來！
Please get off!
我的蛋！
My balls!
山姆！
Sam!
- 我們在哪兒？西姆！
- 嘿！好！
- Where are we? Simmons!  - Hey! Yeah!
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
這是什麼？是維加斯！
What is this? It's Vegas!
都還好嗎？都好！
- You guys okay?  - Yeah!
嘿！到拉斯維加斯了！
Hey! I think we're in Vegas!
確實很疼
That really, really hurts.
你很走運，我沒傷著
You're just lucky that I didn't get hurt.
這樣是要死人的，知道嗎？我要是傷著了
People could've gotten killed, okay? And if I would have gotten hurt,
- 我老媽會問候你…
- 哦，閉嘴！
- you would have heard from...  - Oh, shut up!
我說了要架個時空橋樑
I told you I was opening the space bridge.
這樣到埃及　　　什麼？
It's the fastest way to travel to Egypt.
你在說什麼？你什麼都沒跟我們講！
What did you tell us? You didn't tell us anything!
你什麼都不說，還來埃及幹嘛？
You didn't tell us anything. Why are we in Egypt?
你還敢對我那麼沒禮貌，小混蛋
Don't you dare slip in with me, fleshwing.
- 我原來告訴你了
- 能聽我說兩句嗎？
- You would do the informed.  - Can you just stop for a second?
聽得清吧？你說說為什麼來埃及
Can you focus? Can you tell us why we're in Egypt
至少得讓我們都有點心理準備吧？
so we can all have a little bit assemblance and peace of mind?
這個星球我們機器人以前就來過
This planet was visited by our race once before
第一代祖先百萬年前就來過
by our earliest ancestors a millenium ago.
他們的使命是收集能量塊
They were on an exploratory mission to harvest Energon,
那是機器人的生命之源
the life blood of our race.
沒有它，我們會腐爛，氧化，生銹
Without it, we'll all perish, oxidize and rust,
就像我這身架子
let my wretched self.
你們知道慢慢腐朽而死有多痛苦啊？
Do you have any idea what is like a slowly fall of parton die?
你別總跑題行嗎？老先生
Let's not get episodic, okay? Old-timer.
從頭到尾簡單說出事實和細節，把來龍去脈說清楚
Beginning, middle, end. Facts, details, condense, plot, tell it.
在沙漠的某一處地方
Somewhere buried in this desert, our ancestors built a great machine.
我們的祖先建了個巨型機器，通過摧毀恆星來獲得能量塊
It harvests Energon by destroying suns.
摧毀恆星？把太陽炸掉？
- Destroy suns?  - You mean blow them up?
對，你看，開始的時候
Yes. You see, in the beginning,
曾經有七位超級領袖
there were seven Primes,
都是第一批領袖
our original leaders.
他們進入宇宙尋找其它星系的恆星
And they set out in the Universe seeking distant suns to harvest.
這些超級領袖有一個原則：
The Primes set out with one rule:
決不摧毀有生命的星球
Never destroy a planet with life.
但後來有一位違背了這項原則
Until one of them tried to defy this rule.
他的名字就叫，墮落金剛
And his name, for ever more, was the Fallen.
他不顧人類死活
He despised the human race.
想啟動那個機器來消滅人類
And he wanted to kill you all by turning on that machine.
而激活它的唯一途徑，就是傳說中的鑰匙
The only way to activate it is with a legendary key
也就是我們所說的原能矩陣
called the Matrix of Leadership.
原能矩陣的歸屬問題引發了一場鏖戰
A great battle took place over possession of the Matrix.
墮落金剛比其他超級領袖更強大
The Fallen who was stronger at his will did,
其他超級領袖只能偷出原能矩陣藏起來
surrendered no choice, but to steal and hide it from him.
他們做了最後的犧牲
In the ultimate sacrifice,
以生命為代價將原能矩陣封藏
they gave their lives to seal the Matrix away
藏於用他們遺體鑄成的墳墓裏
in a tomb made of their very own bodies.
這座墓沒有人知道在哪兒
A tomb we cannot find.
就在這沙漠某處
Somewhere, buried in this desert,
埋藏著那台特別的機器
that deadly machine remains.
墮落金剛知道位置
The Fallen knows where it is.
如果他找到了超級領袖的墓
And if he finds the Tomb of the Primes,
你們的世界將不復存在
your world will be no more.
那怎麼阻止他？
Okay so how do we stop it?
只有超級領袖能打敗墮落金剛
Only a Prime can defeat the Fallen.
比如擎天柱？
Optimus Prime?
你遇到過超級領袖嗎？
So you met a Prime?
你遇到的肯定是超級領袖的後代
You must have met a great descendant.
他還活著嗎？
Is he alive?
在這個星球上嗎？
Here? On this planet?
他為了救我犧牲了自己
He sacrificed himself to save me.
那麼他死了
So he's dead.
沒有超級領袖，就不可能了
Without a Prime, it's impossible.
沒人能阻止墮落金剛
No one else could stop the Fallen.
這個能量若能重啟那台機器…
So the same energy that's going to be used to reactivate the machine...
那它能用來激活擎天柱
Could that energy somehow be used to reactivate Optimus
讓他重獲新生嗎？
and bring him back to life?
設計之初並沒這麼考慮
It was never designed for that purpose,
這種力量非比尋常
but it's an energy, like no other.
在霸天虎抓到我之前，你怎麼帶我們找到原能矩陣？
So then how do you get us to the Matrix before the Decepticons get to me?
用你的腦子，地圖，符號
Follow your mind, your map, your symbols,
你在地上寫的，都是線索
what you got in the sand, it's your bloom.
曙光照耀在匕首之尖的時候
When dawn alights the Dagger's tip,
三位國王將打開入口
three kings will reveal the doorway.
找到那入口！
Find the doorway!
快去！
Go now, go!
這曾是我的使命，現在是你的使命了
That was my mission. It's your mission now.
要在霸天虎找到你我之前
Go before the Decepticons find me
先找到入口
and find you.
中情局有線人
That was my CIA contact.
說古代蘇美爾人稱亞喀巴海灣
Says Ancient Sumerian used to call the Gulf of Aqaba
為匕首之尖那是匕首之尖
- the Dagger's Tip.  - That's the dagger's tip.
它是紅海的一部分明白
- It's part of the Red Sea.  - Got it.
一刀為二分出埃及和約旦
It divides Egypt and Jordan like the tip of a blade.
北緯29.5度，東經35度
29 and a half degrees north 35 east.
就是這兒
There it is.
好的，首先得把擎天柱給弄過來
Okay, first thing we gotta do is get Optimus to Dagger's Tip.
怎麼把它繞過大半個地球？
How are you gonna get him halfway around the world?
我打個電話
We're gonna make a call.
有警察
We got the cops.
我不想進監獄，哥們！
I can't go to prison, guys!
山姆，你得離開這條路，避一避
Sam, you gotta get off this road and lay low.
兄弟，他們會發現的
Man, they'll pick up.
這不就是忍者的偽裝術嘛
This is just called blending in like a ninja.
我賞你一巴掌怎麼樣？
How about I'll lay my piss in your face?
他們走了
They're gone.
沒時間了
Wait another time.
打電話給倫諾克
How are you gonna make the call to Lennox?
你可是全球通緝犯，什麼…
You are in the worldwide. What,
他們要埋伏在其中一個基地？
they're gonna tranquil in one base?
他們馬上就會發現你的
They'll track you here in seconds.
中情局就蜂擁而至
CIA is all over this place.
那你來打？
You're gonna call?
好主意，這…主意不錯
Okay, that's... that's a good idea.
好嗎？我是說我只是…
- Alright?  - I mean I just was...
想得有點多了
My mind in other things.
比如你怎麼沒在監獄裏被殺
Like why don't you get being chipped in prison.
（新澤西州）
啟程時間：21點
This departure: 2100 hours.
所以我們要開回基地
So we're shipped in back to base.
中心危在旦夕
This is central at stake.
倫諾克少校，電話
Major Lennox, phone call.
倫諾克，孩子在我旁邊，那孩子，明白嗎？
Lennox, I'm with the kid. The kid, you know?
特有個性的那個？
One with the attitude break?
我們要那卡車，卡車
I need the truck. The truck.
我們有可能讓他起死回生
We got a possible resurrection going on over here.
你想不到我們在哪兒
You're not gonna believe where we are.
線索：法老，圖坦卡門
Code Tot, as in King Tutankhamen,
一美元的背面
back of a $1 bill.
空降坐標如下：北緯29.5度，東經34.88度
Coordinates for air-drop, 29.5 north, 34.88 east.
明白，寫下來，定下來
Get it. Write it down, write it.
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
我得走了，好吧，我恨警察
I gotta go, okay. I hate the cops.
等等，你是誰？
W-Wait, who are you?
等下，是我。裏奧，裏奧，裏奧…
Wait, it's me. Leo, me, Leo, Leo. Leo.
警察來了，快走
The cops are coming right now. We need to go.
坐標，北緯29.5度，東經34.88度
Coordinates 29.5 north, 34.88 east.
紅海的要地，亞喀巴海灣
Tip of the Red Sea, Gulf of Aqaba.
是埃及
Egypt.
你確定嗎？
Are you serious?
長官
Sir.
即使我們真把這大傢伙運到那兒
Even if we could figure out a way to get big man over there.
靠那小孩就能把他救活嗎？
How is this little kid's supposed to bring him back to life?
聽著，我不知道…
I don't know.
但必須相信他
But we gotta trust him.
好，我們再複述一遍
Okay, let's go over it again.
當曙光照耀…
When the dawn arise...
當曙光照耀在匕首之尖的時候
When the dawn arise the dagger's tip,
三位國王……將打開入口
- the three kings...  - ...will reveal the doorway.
這是他原話，知道意思嗎？
That's what he said. You know what that means?
不，不知道啊我也不清楚
- No, what does it mean?  - I have no idea.
哦，我的天，糟了，檢查站，檢查站
Oh my God, oh my God. Checkpoint, checkpoint.
我沒帶護照
I don't have my passport.
護照，快點拿出護照來，笨蛋！
Passport. Idiota!
上面有攝像頭
They have cams at top.
這就是他們要找的人
He's the one that they want.
好了，放鬆，得有個間諜樣
Alright, chill. Let's be nice to them.
我能搞定，這都是我的人
I can handle it. These are my people.
好我１３６
- Yeah.  - I'm 136.
哦，很好，一個瘋小子
Oh great, a frickin' munchkin.
哦，小個子都這樣。告訴他，他很高
Oh, little people are mean. Tell him he's tall.
你要什麼？我想去…
- What do you want?  - I want to go to...
匕首之尖，對吧？
The Dagger's Tip, right?
埃及，約旦，我們想去那兒
Egypt, Jordan. We wanna go there.
我和我的家人，這是我的家人
Me and my family. This is my family.
- 這是我大兒子
- 嗨，你好
- This is my son, my other son.  - Hi there.
二兒子…我的女兒
My daughter.
我們是來旅遊的，從紐約來
We're tourists from New York.
紐約？對，對
- New York?  - Yes. Yes.
五十公里就到
50 kilometres.
我們去買你們的三明治，謝謝！
We're going to get one of your falafels, thank you!
好的，謝謝你
Yeah, thank you very much.
- 紐約
- 我知道，我們在哪兒見過你
- New York.  - I know, I know you from somewhere.
不，我們不是中情局的
No, we do not work for the CIA.
霸天虎，注意
Decepticons, voice location.
男孩的位置已經探明
Detected.
紅蜘蛛跟著
注意隱蔽，你得把自己偽裝起來
Undercover, yo, you gotta blend in with your surrounding.
和周圍融為一體
You know, you gotta be part of the landscape.
壯觀
Awesome.
應該是外星人建的
I think aliens built that.
對，對，對
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
來，快點！快點
Go, move it! Move it.
什麼？嘿，保護我們
- What?  - Hey, guard us.
低調點，別一驚一乍的，好嗎？
Low-profile, don't make a scene, okay?
某些人有活要干啦！
Yeah, some of us got work to do!
笨蛋汽車人
Dumb Autobots.
（巢穴部隊到達時間 - 早上6點）
Estimated time of detachment NEST, 0600 AM
做我女朋友其實挺危險
Being my girlfriend is hazardous to your health.
沒錯，嗯…女孩就喜歡愛冒險的男生
Yeah, well, girls like dangerous boys.
真的？對
- Really?  - Yeah.
你還是說出來吧？
Why don't you say it?
女士優先
Ladies first.
好吧，你今晚很紳士
Okay, so tonight, you're gonna be a gentleman.
挺有風度的
You're really chivalrous.
為什麼生我的氣？
Why are you mad at me?
你知道嗎？寶貝，我沒…
You know what? Baby, I'm not...
我沒生氣
I'm not mad.
我飛了三千公里，就是不想看到你死
You realise that I just flew 3,000 miles to keep you from getting killed.
我知道
I know.
誰還能當你女朋友？
Who else could be your girlfriend too?
看看我們所經歷的一切
Look at the things that go through with me.
現在我們有月光和星光
And now we're underneath the moon and the stars
有地球上三個最漂亮的金字塔
and the three most beautiful pyramids on the planet
你還是不肯說你愛我
and you still can't even tell me that you love me.
怎麼？等等
- What?  - Wait.
- 你又轉移話題？
- 金字塔和星星…
- Why do boys always change the subject?  - The moon and the stars...
山姆…跟我來，快
- Sam...  - Come with me really quick.
西蒙，裏奧，快醒醒！
Simmons, Leo, wake up!
聽著，天文學課本第47頁，你還記得嗎？
Listen, Astronomy class, page 47, you remember the class?
不，不，記得嗎…我只上了兩天大學，你記得什麼？
No, no, I was only in college for two days, you remember that?
- 對，起來，起來，過來
- 他說什麼呢？
- Yeah, well, get up. Up, up.  - What are you talking about?
看到那三顆星星了嗎？
Can you see those three stars?
最下面一顆貼著地平線？
You see how the last one touches the horizon?
那是獵戶座
That's Orion's belt.
也叫做三王星，因為…
It's also called the Three Kings and the reason for that is
三位埃及國王專門在吉薩建造了金字塔
the three Egyptian kings who built the pyramids in Giza built them
來對應三顆星星
to mear those stars.
它們像箭一樣擺在咱們面前
So it's like an aerial staring straight in the face.
他們指向東方，約旦的方向
They all point due east towards Jordan.
指向佩特拉的群山
The mountains of Petra.
引擎發生故障，已向中央司令部緊急報告…
We got a seatbelt malfunction. We gotta have to divert...
減輕負載，準備跳傘
Flight in lower, prepare for bail-out.
跳傘，跳傘，跳傘，跳傘？
Bail-out, bail-out, bail-out, bail-out?
好了，所有人，背好降落傘
Alright, team, grab your shoots.
跳傘？
Bail-out?
用過軍用降落傘嗎？
Familiar with the standard MC-4?
當然沒有
Of course not.
我沒在這麼好的飛機上跳過傘
I've never jumped out of a publicly good airplane before.
等一下，你不是捉弄我吧？
Wait a minute, is this really happening?
嗯
Yeah.
等等，等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
是你在背後操縱，是吧？
You're behind this, aren't you?
說什麼呢？
What are you talking about?
按廣播說的辦，這些人不會胡鬧
You heard the pilot. These guys don't mess around.
這是工作流程，我只是奉命行事
This is standard procedure. I'm just following orders to the letter.
這不是你說的嗎？
Do you know what you said?
你，剛找到領導和你的事業…
You, just find the captain and your career...
等等，那是什麼？那是什麼？
Wait, what was that? What's that?
情況不妙
That's not good.
快點，這邊來，這邊！
Come on. Right this way, right this way!
我不能跳下去
I can't jump out of an airplane.
這邊來，來啊
Come here. Come here.
你怎麼不帶降落傘？
Why don't you get your chute?
我必須要保證最重要的人先走
Because I have to secure the VIPs first.
好了，我希望你能全部聽清楚
Okay, I want you to listen very carefully.
記住我跟你說的每句話好
- Remember as everything that I say.  - OK.
每個降落傘都有GPS
East to the GPS trackers,
這樣方便展開搜救
so you can be found by search and rescue.
而且在每個降落傘邊上有條帶子
用帶子把扣拉開就能打開主背囊
聽明白了嗎？我聽不清
- Look, are you listening?  - I can't.
好吧，好吧好吧
- Alright, alright.  - Alright.
當飛機遇到氣流膨脹了
When the plane that shoot inflates into the air,
它會拉動鎖扣打開降落傘
pull the pin and open some air,
紅色的備用，藍色是主傘
red is for your back up, blue's your primary.
我要你拉藍色的
I want you to pull the blue.
你可要使勁拉
I need you to pull it really hard.
不，別現在拉，你還在飛機上，白癡！
Not right now. We're on the plane, you dumbass!
他說再見了嗎？
Did he say goodbye?
沒有，沒來得及說
No, he didn't even say goodbye.
將軍，我們已就緒
General, we're loaded and ready.
你一旦下令，五分鐘後開始行動
You give us the go, and we'll be ready to press in five minutes.
很好長官
- Excellent.  - Sir,
你看這個，看
you need to see this. Now.
（從倫諾克：北緯29.5，東京35.88）
這個坐標在哪兒？
Have we checked these coordinates?
在埃及，長官，他們在那裏空降
Egypt, sir. They're air-dropping in.
開什麼玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
他知道
He knows something.
如果他要行動，我們會給他支援
We need to be ready to back him up, if this thing goes hot.
收到
Copy that.
中情局找到那個男孩了
CIA just got a hit on the boy.
距倫諾克空降點一百公里
Hundred miles from the location on that little map there.
花樣真多
It's getting hotter.
它應該…就在這附近了
It's gotta be... around here somewhere.
這也太壯觀了，看到了嗎？
太雄偉了！不可思議
太棒了
就是這兒，各位
It's here somewhere, guys.
哦，是嗎，憑什麼？
Oh yeah, why?
那個機器人自己都老糊塗了
'Cause we're trusting Grandpa Blackbird
都不知道他自己在什麼星球上
who doesn't even know what planet he's on.
說實話，這是我這輩子…
On his defense, this is the biggest doorway
見過的最大的門了
I've ever seen in my entire life.
好吧，不錯，我先摸摸底，好吧？
Okay. Well, that's great. Let me do a quick search, alright?
不
Nope.
壞消息是，夥計們，考古學家已經來過了
Ever questioned mind, guys, that archaeologists have been here before.
這兒什麼都沒有
There's nothing here.
生活免不了痛苦和絕望，孩子
You realise it's heart-break, despair, kid.
有時候，你付出了很多
Sometimes, you get to the end of the rainbow
但老天爺就是要開玩笑
and the leprechauns went and booby-trapped it.
你還說我，你還離不開你老媽
I'm listening to you; you live with your mother.
- 還沒有結束
- 結束了，早完了
- It's not over.  - It is over. It's done.
為什麼你們總是說傻話？
Why are we still listening to your little punk-ass?
我是說，有這功夫…還不如把我的輪子弄漂亮點？
I mean, what kind of dumbfucks accept ding my rim?
幹掉威震天，如何？
Kill Megatron. How about that?
他沒完成心願，你知道我的意思
Well, he doesn't get the job done, you know, I mean,
- 因為他被打了，兄弟
- 你害怕了？
- 'cause he's zapped, man.  - You scared?
什麼，害怕？我害怕你那張醜臉
Well, scared? Scared of your ugly face.
我醜？咱倆是雙胞胎，蠢材
I'm ugly? Well, we twins, you stupid genius.
兄弟們！哦，嘿！
Guys! Oh, hey!
你喜歡這滋味嗎？
You like the way that feels?
那不疼你明白吧，嗯？
- That ain't hurt.  - You got that, don't you?
我要起來了…
I'm getting up...
太無禮了
Now that's rude.
哦，天哪！是符號
Oh, my God! The symbols.
大黃蜂！射穿它
Bee! Shoot it.
看啊
Check this.
哇！
Wow!
這就是天火說的元老
This is the part which they found silicon.
超級領袖的墳墓
The Tomb of the Primes.
原能矩陣
The Matrix.
不
No
千年寶物化為灰燼
Thousands of years turned to dust.
結果不該是這樣
This isn't how it's supposed to end.
聽到了嗎？
Hear that?
美國空軍，C-17S
US Air Force. C-17s.
擎天柱救不活了，什麼都沒了
You can't bring it back, Sam, there's nothing left.
看，你看看周圍
Look, look around you.
我們所做的一切都事出有因
We didn't just go through everything we went through for no reason at all.
結局並不重要
They just haven't end like this.
重要的是我們來這裏的原因
There is a reason that we're here.
我大腦裏的聲音和符號指引了…
The voices and the symbols in my head led us here...
目標
for a purpose.
大家跟著我，是因為我有線索
Everyone's after me because of what I know.
而我所知的，就是這個管用
And what I know, is that this is going to work.
你怎麼知道會管用？
How do you know it's going to work?
因為我相信它
Because I believe it.
你們最好讓我離開這架飛機
Best put me out of this plane.
在放大傢伙了，山姆！
He's dropping the big one. Sam!
你用這些黑沙子就能救擎天柱？
You think you can bring him back to life with that pixie dust?
當然可以，走吧！
Absolutely. Let's go!
走！
Go!
快點！
Move it!
記住，他們是朋友！
Remember your friendly!
把擎天柱隱蔽起來！
Cover Optimus!
全村警戒，把彈藥放到這來
Secure the village. Get those cases down here.
佈置狙擊手和導彈
Get snipers and Stingers up high.
我們把這十噸重的機器人
So he just dropped off ten tonnes of dead robot
運到這不毛之地
in the middle of nowhere.
希望這孩子心裏有數
Hope this little kid know what he's doing.
對，我也這麼想
Yeah, me too.
發現目標！大黃蜂，四公里
Got a visual! Yellow tee, four klicks.
發信號彈！
Hot-flare!
他們在哪兒，看到嗎？
That's them right there. You see the flare?
就在那兒！看到嗎？
Right over there! See it?
男孩已找到
不
No.
山姆！
Sam!
哦，上帝，求求你，上帝
Oh God, please God,
拜託！裏奧，別說了！
- please!  - Leo, stop freaking out.
- 不要再叫了！
- 把這傢伙扔下去吧，嗯？
- Just stop freaking out!  - Just drop this guy off, huh?
- 求你了，讓我活著，別讓我死
- 閉嘴！
- Please let me live, just let me live.  - Stop freaking out!
馬上停止尖叫，就是這樣
Just stop screaming right now. That's it.
受不了這傢伙了
Can't take that guy anymore.
用灰塵作掩護，我們得分開
We gotta split up.
大黃蜂，你上去引開霸天虎，好嗎？
Bumblebee, you are the decoy. You lead the Decepticons away, alright?
我去找擎天柱
I'm gonna get Optimus.
我和雙胞胎車去把他們引開
I'll help throw their fire away.
你找那些士兵去
You get to those soldiers.
希望你能成功，孩子
I hope that dust works, kid.
謝謝
Thank you.
他轉回來了
It's turning around.
他回來了，他回來了
It's coming back, it's coming back.
交給我了
It's up to me.
一個老光棍，愛國卻被拋棄
One man, alone, betrayed by the country he loves,
可在危難時刻又成為最後的希望
now its last hope in the final hour of need.
準備由一代宗師駕駛你吧
The pants are to be driven like never before.
大師風範
Under my skin.
嘿，嘿，嘿！哪兒也別去
Hey, hey, hey! Don't go nowhere.
開車你幹不了這個，孩子
- Drive!  - You will never make it, kid.
光靠勇敢是不夠的
Bravery will only get you so far.
你電暈過我，對嗎？你欠我的
You tased me, okay? You owe me.
我要去好吧，好吧
- I'm go.  - Okay, okay.
我是考驗你的，你過關了好嗎？
That was a test. You passed, alright?
那東西帶著霸天虎的標誌
Thing's got alien tattoos all over.
不是空軍
That ain't Air Force.
那是什麼鬼東西？
What the hell was that?
Eddy-1，收到　　　有人收到嗎？
- Eddy-1, copy.  - Anyone there?
有人嗎？
Who's up?
收到通信中斷
- Copy.  - Radio's down.
不起作用了
It's dead. Counter that.
電磁脈衝干擾
EMP-burst.
看看今天在這鬼地方會發生什麼
Let's see how this day is going in this godforsaken desert.
你好，長官
Yes, sir.
倫諾克少校叫我把電話轉給你
Major Lennox told me to pull the cord.
我知道，長官
I know, sir.
我…我現在在哪個國家？
W... Which, what country am I in right now?
美利堅
United States.
不，不，不是美國，我就是從美國來的
No, no, not the United States. I'm from the United States,
鬼知道是什麼地方，四周都是驢
I'm in the middle of nowhere, surrounded by goats.
那是我們的好朋友蓋洛威
Well, that was our good friend, Galloway.
看來他有點不高興
He's less than pleased.
真是怪了，我們聯繫不到倫諾克
How is it that we can't reach our men,
他怎麼能在那寸草不生的埃及沙漠裏聯繫到我們？
but he can reach me from some random Egyptian desert?
沒有
Nothing.
發求救信號，告訴衛星我們需要幫助
Mike, put an SOS, let the eye in the sky know we need some help.
是，長官　　　準備氣罐
Yes, sir. Prepare the gas can.
多放點煙，好讓那孩子找到我們
Pop some more flares so that the kid can find us.
就是那兒，到了
There he is. We got a couple of miles.
倫諾克的隊伍擁有最先進的量子通訊器材
Lennox's team has the latest in quantum crypto gear.
誰能告訴我為什麼我們連簡單的通信連接都不能夠建立？
Can somebody tell me why we can't establish simple radio contact?
我們正在嘗試所有可用的頻段和模式，長官
We're hailing them on every frequency and mode in the book, sir.
那個區域的衛星已經不能工作了
Our satellites in the area have gone blind.
我們正在努力，長官
We're working it, sir.
見鬼
Dammit.
想想別的方法，聯繫友軍
Something's not right, it doesn't add up.
看看能否派空軍前去
Contact the Jordanians, see what their assets they've got in the area.
還有聯絡薩勒姆將軍
And get Egypt's General Salaam,
讓他派出無人偵察機飛越那片領空
ask him to clear some US V over-flights in Egyptian airspace.
我們現在需要各方幫助確認地點
We need an assist in confirming visuals now.
無人機起飛
Scramble predators now.
B-1號，起飛
B-1, rotate.
還有一英里
East on the mile that way.
來這裏
Come here.
這邊
This way.
- 一個…老光棍…
- 別再說了
- One man... alone...  - Stop saying that.
- 愛國卻被祖國拋棄
- 哦，我的天啊
- betrayed by the country he loves.  - Oh my goodness,
我還在車裏呢，好吧？你不是一個人
I'm in the car, okay? You're not alone.
放鬆，我可是大師
Just relax, you're looking nice well.
我…我覺得他們已經被甩掉了
I... I don't think he's still following us.
那是你覺得
That's what you think.
主人，很遺憾地告訴你個壞消息
Master, sorry to be the bearer of bad news,
他們把擎天柱運來了
but the soldiers brought the body of Prime.
那男孩肯定找到原能矩陣了
The boy must have the Matrix.
不能讓他接近擎天柱
We cannot let him reach Optimus.
霸天虎們！
Decepticons!
我們開始攻擊！
Begin our assault!
有情況！
We got incoming!
保持好隊形，加強火力！
We got a whole load of flight coming our way!
有多少？大概十三個
- How many?  - We got 13 to count.
不吉利，真不吉利
This ain't good. This ain't good.
我們這回可慘了
We 'bout to get our asses whooped.
那些霸天虎正在尋找山姆
Alright, those Decepticons are searching for Sam.
不管怎麼樣，他肯定能夠救活擎天柱
Whatever he has, he thinks it'll bring Optimus back to life.
我們任務就是找到他，幫他救活擎天柱
So our mission is to find him and get him to Optimus.
好，我們由左翼吸引火力
Alright, we're gonna draw fire from the left flag.
我需要偵察隊，我帶隊
I need a scout team.
阿爾茜和鐵皮從中路上
We'll walk through the middle with Arcee and Ironhide.
當你們看到有綠色的煙霧時
Alright, when you see the precious cargo,
就穿過那些柱子回來
I want you to pop green smoke and come back to those pillars.
我們打個伏擊戰
We'll have the ambush set.
好的，出發，出動！
Alright, let's go, move out!
出動！出動！
- Move out!  - Move out!
看過五七年那部伯特·蘭凱斯特的經典槍戰片嗎？
Did you see that film Gunfire Aero-Kay Karao?
- 科克·道格拉斯演的
- 沒有，怎麼了？
- Casting Kirk Douglas.  - No, why?
我們和他們處境一樣
Looks like we're right in the middle of it.
結果好嗎？
Is that good?
很多人都死了
Lot of people died.
哦，哦，哦…隱蔽起來！
- Oh, oh, oh...  - Hide!
我的天！
Oh my God!
山姆，山姆
Sam, Sam.
蹲下，蹲下
Get down, get down.
好，聽著，我們現在以最快速度
Once, it's clear, we'll run for Optimus
跑到擎天柱那兒，好嗎？
as fast we can, okay?
要是不行怎麼辦？
And what if it doesn't work?
一定能行
This will work.
- 是啊，但是如果不行呢？
- 一定行
- Yeah, but what if it doesn't?  - It's gonna work.
一定行
It'll work.
快走，快走…
Go Go...
準備跳
Radio shell.
還有半英里
We got a half a mile.
士兵們不知道我們在這兒
I don't think the soldiers know we're here.
撤退！
Fall back!
鐵皮，到中間來
Ironhide, up for middle.
鐵皮，快走
Ironhide, move it.
走！走，走！
Go! Go, go!
我們被困了，無路可走，要死了！
There's no way to go. We're gonna die!
聽著，就算死，也要死得像爺們，明白嗎？
Listen, we're going out. We're going out like men, understand?
我們要死了！
We're gonna die!
哦你瞧這傢伙…
- Oh.  - Look at this motherf...
霸天虎真差勁！
Mean robots suck!
堅持
Hang on
回來！
Get back!
抓住！別放開
Grab it! Don't let go.
堅持，老哥，我抓住了
Hang in, man, I got this.
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
我抓住了，我使勁抓住了
Careful grip, boy. Careful grip.
你不會吃了我…不，不，不
You can't eat me... no no no.
他做到了，他真浪費
He did. He got so waste.
現在誰是你爸，嗯？
Who's your daddy now, huh?
他被整個都吃了…
He got all these...
唯一安全的地方就是它的下面
Well, the safe place is right under it.
朝它跑，朝它的腳跑！
Run it. Run for his feet!
你就不該吃我，我要把你的臉砸爛
You're never eating me. I'm gonna bust your face up.
好戲開始了，小心你的臉！
Nobody's tested me. In your face!
接著打，哥們
Take five, Mudflap.
哦，天哪！
Oh my God!
沒人能欺負雙胞胎兄弟
Nobody messes with the twins.
我抓到你了
I got you.
夥計，你打到我的臉了！
Ow, man, you shot me in the face!
- 呆在下面！
- 對，呆在它下面
- Stay under it!  - Yeah, stay under it.
這是圈套
朱迪！
Judy!
山姆！什麼？
- Sam!  - What?
山姆！
Sam!
山姆！山姆！
Sam! Sam!
山姆！
Sam!
山姆爸爸！
- Sam.  - Dad!
等等！等等！
Wait! Wait!
請聽…
Please listen...
我要你跑！快跑！
I want you to run! Run!
爸，別說了！快離開這裏
- Dad, just stop!  - Get out of here.
- 他們要的不是你們，是我
- 快跑！
- They don't want you, they want me.  - Just run!
哦，天哪，等等！
Oh God, wait!
薩姆爾·維基等等
- Samuel Witwicky.  - Wait.
這是你想要的，你要的是這個
This is what you want. You don't want 'em.
- 快走！快走！
- 求你們別說了！別說了！
- Go! Go!  - Please, stop! Stop!
為什麼你…快離開這兒！
- Why don't you...  - Just get out of here!
別傷害他們
Just don't move.
我知道你
I know you.
快走！快走！
Just go! Just go!
我知道你要的是我
And I know what, you need me.
因為我知道原能矩陣
Because I know about the Matrix.
- 別這麼做，山姆，聽我說
- 拜託，爸
- Don't do it. Sam, listen to me.  - Please, Dad.
他們一樣會殺了我們
They're gonna kill us all anyway.
嘿，嘿，看
Hey, hey. Look.
你想要的東西，在我這裏
This is what you want. I'm here.
大黃蜂！
Bumblebee!
救命！
Help!
殺了他，大黃蜂，殺了他
Kill him, Bee. Kill him.
快點，到這兒來
Come on, get in.
大黃蜂？在
- Bee?  - Yeah.
嘿！我不知道發生了什麼，但我們必須得離開
Hey! I don't know what's going on, but we gotta move.
快跑！這裏肯定有出路的
- Run!  - There's gotta be a way out of here.
靠著牆，靠著牆，過來這裏
Buckle up, buckle up! Get in here.
大黃蜂！大黃蜂！
Bee! Bumblebee!
你把他們帶到安全的地方，好嗎？
You get them somewhere safe, alright?
你們到車裏去，那裏安全
You gotta get in the car. You can be safe.
不，現在還爭什麼爭
No, listen to my discussion.
- 你是我的兒子，對吧？
- 我知道！
- You're my son, alright?  - I know!
你是我的兒子！我們要在一起
You're my son! We'll all go together.
聽著我們要在一起
- Listen.  - We're all going together.
爸，別說了，好嗎？你們快上車
Dad, stop, okay? Get in the car.
他會把你帶到安全的地方，不安全就跑
He's gonna get you to safety. You don't, you run.
別停下，也別躲，使勁跑
You don't stop, you don't hide, you run.
聽到我說的了嗎？
You hear what I'm saying?
好嗎？你們安全了我就來
Okay? I'll find you when you're safe.
- 不
- 讓我自己做該做的事情，爸
- No.  - You gotta let me go, Dad.
讓我自己來
You'll have to let me go.
我必須自己來羅恩
- You have to.  - Ron.
羅恩，羅恩！讓他去吧
Ron, Ron! Let him go.
你一定要回來！
Just come back!
走吧！走吧！
- Come on!  - Come on!
米卡拉，米卡拉！
Mikaela, Mikaela!
- 跟他們一起去
- 我不能沒有你
- Go with my parents.  - I'm not gonna go with them.
友軍來了！我們有救了！
- We got Jordanians!  - We got help!
臥倒
Get dowm
你沒事吧，士兵？
You okay, soldier?
我們來幫你，士兵
We're gonna help you, soldier.
把飛機裏的傷員救出來！
Let's get being moon and clear the birds!
別動，別動，先別動
Stay still, stay still. Don't move.
你還好嗎，年輕人？
You alright, young man?
有無線電嗎？有
- You have a radio?  - Yes.
嘿，孩子，認識你還是很高興的
Hey kid, it's been nice knowing you.
記住我為我的國家所做的
Remember what I did for my country.
我死而無憾
This is my moment.
你瘋了！
You're crazy!
大約兩分鐘內到達指定位置
ETA to station, two minutes.
- 放在主屏幕上顯示
- 長官，是，長官
- Put it on the main screen.  - Sir, yes, sir.
捕食者無人機，一號
Predator's air-one.
哦，糟糕，上當了
Oh shit, it's a trick.
給我下令開始「烈焰」行動，傳達到每個人
Commence Operation Firestorm. Send everyone.
海軍陸戰隊準備出發
Get those boys out of the ground.
我是總部
This is 101 in strike packages.
展開攻擊編隊，輕裝上陣
Fast course river. Execute lightly.
看到山姆了快點，別拖拉！
- Spotted Sam.  - Hurry, don't slow up!
鐵皮！
Ironhide!
跟著我們去柱子那邊，我們帶你去擎天柱那裏
Follow us to the pillars. We'll take you to Optimus.
小心！
Look out!
山姆，到柱子那邊！
Sam, get to the pillars!
我們走
Let's go.
哦，天啊，在那兒
Oh God, this is it.
金字塔就建在機器上面
The pyramids built right over the machine.
他們啟動機器…
They turn that machine on...
太陽就沒了
no more Sun.
我可不答應
Not on my watch.
我絕對不答應
我是美軍斯滕尼斯號航母艦長，請報明身份
USS Stennis, identify.
嘿，你到底在哪兒？
Hey, where the hell are you?
什麼，在看氣象頻道嗎？
What, you're on a weather channel?
還是體育新聞，情景是喜劇還是什麼？
Sports center, high-dreaming TV or something?
我們有三百顆衛星在天上
We get a pretty hundred satellites up there.
可我們的人都在哪兒？
Where the hell are all our men?
請報上你的身份
Identify yourself.
你叫什麼，水手？
What is your name, sailor?
懷爾德，我是美國海軍斯滕尼斯號航母的艦長
Wilder, Captain of the USS John C. Stennis Aircraft Carrier.
好吧，懷爾德艦長
Okay, Captain Wilder,
我是特工西蒙，第七區的頭
this is Agent Seymour Simmons, head of the Sector Seven.
有個極其強大的外星人
There is a mother of all non-biologicals
正準備摧毀太陽
getting ready to blow up our Sun.
你是要繼續跟我爭論官階高低
You want to have fooled down about my lack of clearance,
還是去拯救億萬人的性命呢？
or you want to help save a gazillion lives?
好吧，西蒙，我聽著呢
Alright, Agent Simmons. I'm listening.
五公里
Five klicks.
海灣以西
West of the gulf.
一個外星人正在摧毀金字塔
We got ourselves a dalion remodelling a pyramid.
我們唯一的希望就是那門軌道炮
I want hopes of prototype weapon pull a rail gun.
能以七倍音速擊穿鋼板
這屬於機密
That's classified.
別跟我說什麼機密，好嗎？
Don't talk to me about classified, alright?
如果你的船到了海灣，你就明白了
Now if you've got a battleship in the gulf, you'll do.
叫他們準備發射武器！
you tell him to ready that weapon!
呼叫基德號，驅逐艦
Contact Destroyer, USS Kit.
這裏！過來！
This way! Move it!
- 我們應該去哪兒，長官？
- 組成攻擊隊形
- What you need is there?  - Form attack.
快點！快！
Let's go! Go!
把無線電給我，快點
Give me your talk. Come on.
普斯！
Epps!
我們需要空中支援
Right now, we need air support.
我們的士兵在20英里以北…
That ship's in contact. 20 miles...
聯繫的區域，88區，AS
Grid on contact. Proceed 88, Alpha Sierra.
美軍轟炸機，０９０，你可以準備投射聯合攻擊彈藥…
USS Stenin 0-9-0, you are approved to drop a 2,000...
- 情況怎樣？
- 一個炸彈，長官
- What you got?  - A detonator, sir.
我們沒有接到他們，他們跑向柱子那邊了
They're 600 minutes away and they're heading right for the pillars.
好的
Alright.
空中支援快到了
Precious cargo's coming.
行動！
Move!
山姆
Sam!
發現山姆
Spotted Sam.
快點！
Come on!
2-2，火力掩護，有兩個人，十二點方向
2-2, covering fire. Two civilians, twelve o'clock.
掩護我們
Cover for us.
好，保持空襲火力，我們在營救那兩個人
Okay, air strike. We'll rescue the civilians.
快點，過來！
Come on. Get up!
快點！
Come on!
進去
Get in here.
讓我們到這兒來
Oh look who showed up.
你最好給個充分的理由
You better have a good reason for us to be here.
擎天柱在哪兒？
Where's Optimus?
他就在院子那邊
He's right over there, across the courtyard.
那我就去找他
I got to get to him right now.
不，沒有空中掩護
No, we got an air strike coming.
我必須馬上見到他
I have to get to him right now.
退後，退後
Come here, b-back.
漂亮的落地！
Incoming!
瞧瞧我天火的英姿吧！
Behold to the only Jetfire!
現在讓我給大家展示一下如何讓敵人痛苦
Now let me show you how we brought them pain in my day.
我太老了
Too old for this crap.
繼續前進
Keep going.
十五回合的戰鬥
15 minutes of fighting.
我就在大力神的下面
I am directly below the enemy's scrotum.
海平面上25.7米
25.7 metres above sea level,
北緯29.32度
29.32 north.
-發射軌道，5-2，5點方向 -目標鎖定
- Field track, 5-2, 0500 o'clock.  - Target acquired.
保持鎖定，2號軌道
Killing track two.
鎖定，發射
Lock. Fire.
太好了！太好了！
Yeah! Yeah!
B1轟炸機，30秒後接近目標…
B-1, stand on my target. 30 seconds...
好的，我們現在必須轉移了，明白嗎？
We're gonna make a break for the beast on my command, okay?
你們兩個就跟著我跑，明白嗎？
You guys stick with me, you understand?
一步也不許離開
You stay on my ass.
希望那些F16能打准點
Hope these F-16s got good aim.
嗯，怎麼了？
Yeah, why is that?
我告訴他們橘紅色煙霧為打擊目標
I told them to hit the orange smoke.
你是說橘紅色的煙霧嗎？
You mean that orange smoke?
這不是我扔得最好的一次，懂嗎？
It wasn't my best toss, okay?
準備，開火
快跑！快跑！
- Run!  - Run!
來啦！
Incoming!
快點
Come on.
去死吧！
Die!
山姆！
Sam!
別開火！
Hold your fire!
山姆！
Sam!
走開！快去叫救護車
Get out! Get me an EVAC.
不能做點什麼嗎？
Can't you do something?
山姆！山姆…山姆！
- Sam! Sam...  - Sam!
快點，我們走，我們走，快點！
Come on, we got to move. We got to move! Come on!
山姆！
Sammy!
準備！電擊，準備！電擊
Clear! Take a shot. Clear! Take a shot.
一、二、三
One, two, three.
別再這樣
Do it again.
山姆！
Sam!
好了，聽我的聲音，我愛你，我需要你
Okay, listen to my voice. I love you and I need you.
拜託，拜託，為了我回來，山姆，拜託！我愛你！
Please, please come back to me. Sam, please! I love you!
我死了嗎？
Am I dead?
我們一直在關注你很長，很長時間了
We have been watching you. A long, long time.
你為擎天柱而戰鬥
You have fought for Optimus,
我們唯一的後代，你英勇無畏，不怕犧牲
our last descendant, with courage and with sacrifice.
具有領袖精神
The virtues of a leader.
我們值得將秘密托付給你
A leader worthy of our secret.
原能矩陣不是被發現的
The Matrix of Leadership is not found.
而是通過努力得來的
It is earned.
回到擎天柱身邊
Return now to Optimus,
將他的火種源融合到原能矩陣中
merge the Matrix with his Spark.
那是你此生注定的命運
It is, and always has been, your destiny.
山姆
Sam.
我愛你
I love you.
孩子，你為我而回來
Boy, you returned for me.
活著的超級領袖！
A living Prime!
簡直不敢相信
I don't believe it.
我的原能矩陣
My Matrix.
站起來，站起來，站起來…
Get up, get up, get up, get up.
站起來，擎天柱！
Get up, Prime!
哦，不他要摧毀太陽
- Oh, no.  - He's turned on the machine.
你要阻止他，站起來！
You gotta stop him. Get up!
擎天柱！
Optimus!
墮落金剛，我的主人
Fallen, my master.
其他那些超級領袖都不能阻擋我
My brothers could not stop me from this.
對現在，太陽是我的了
- Yes.  - Now I claim your sun.
向金字塔頂射擊
Enemy target, top of pyramid.
行動，行動，行動
Engage, engage, engage.
很快，我們的力量會更強大
In moments, we'll be at siren strength.
我當霸天虎的日子裏，今天才真正做了件值得做的事情
I never did a thing worth doing until now.
擎天柱，收下我的禮物
Optimus, take my parts.
這能量之強大，你無法預料
And you'll have a power you've never known.
請完成你的使命
Fulfill your destiny.
汽車人，通電！
Jolt, electrify!
移植加力燃燒器
出擊
Let's roll.
開火，瞄準金字塔！
Fire. Take it off to the pyramid!
這個星球將永遠陷入黑暗中
This planet will be dark forever.
和你的兄弟們一樣去死
Die like your brother.
他們也是你的兄弟
They were your brothers too.
紅蜘蛛…
First gra...
你選錯了目標！
You picked the wrong planet!
拿下你的面罩
Give me your face.
我贏了，你失敗了
I rise. You fall.
不，不
No. No.
我不想勸你做膽小鬼，主人，但是，有時侯…
Not to call you a coward, Master, but sometimes,
膽小鬼往往能生存下來
cowards do survive.
這不算完
This isn't over.
經歷了這一切你才願意說你愛我
You took all of this for you to tell me that you love me.
你先說的
You said it first.
謝謝你，山姆，你救了我的命
Thank you, Sam, for saving my life.
別客氣
You're welcome.
謝謝你信任我
Thank you for believing in me.
我們的種族因為被遺忘的過去而走到一起
Our races united by a history long forgotten.
齊心協力，面對未來
And a future we shall face together.
我是擎天柱，在此發出倡議
I am Optimus Prime, and I send this message
讓這段歷史流傳下去
so that our past will always be remembered.
我們擁有珍貴的記憶，生生不息
For in those memories, we live on.
導演：邁克爾·貝
編劇：厄倫·克魯格　　 　　　羅貝爾多·奧爾奇 　　　阿力克斯·庫茲曼
取材於孩之寶的變形金剛動畫人物
製片：洛倫佐·迪·博納文圖拉
製片：湯姆·德桑托 與 唐·墨菲
製片：伊恩·布萊斯
很高興你能來聽課,愛因斯坦教授
So glad you can join us, Professoer Einstein.
對，最近有點忙
Yeah, I was kind of busy.
好了
OK.
執行製片：史蒂芬·斯皮爾伯格 　　　　　邁克爾·貝
執行製片：布萊恩·戈德諾 　　　　　馬克·瓦拉迪恩
攝影指導：本·薜辛
藝術指導：奈傑爾·費爾普斯
剪輯：羅傑·巴頓　 　　　保羅·拉貝爾
剪輯：喬爾·內古龍　 　　　托馬斯·馬爾登
服裝設計：黛博拉·琳恩·斯科特
音　樂 斯蒂夫·賈布隆斯基 片尾曲 林肯公園
視覺特效：斯科特·法拉
主演：希亞·拉博夫
主演：梅根·福克斯
主演：喬什·杜哈明
主演：泰瑞斯·吉布森
主演：凱文·杜恩
主演：朱麗葉·懷特
拉蒙·羅德裏格茲 約翰·本傑明·西基
伊莎貝爾·盧卡斯 格倫·莫肖爾 馬修·馬斯登
與：約翰·特托羅
選角導演：丹尼斯·查米安